<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/category/.business.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 14:29:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>Can You as a CFO survive the journey of leading a pre-IPO company to IPO?</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/posts/2012/02/can-you-as-a-cfo-survive-the-journey-of-leading-a-pre-ipo-company-to-ipo/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When you join a pre-IPO company as its CFO, the holy grail (well, for most) is to get this baby to IPO. It brings fame, exit money, and an enviable career achievement that will always give you a boardroom directorship for post-exit retirement life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decision tree illustrates potential roadblocks along this journey and helps you figure if your set-up has all the right elements for your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/IPO-tree.jpg" alt="IPO Survival Tree", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 14:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-02-24:posts/2012/02/can-you-as-a-cfo-survive-the-journey-of-leading-a-pre-ipo-company-to-ipo/</guid><category></category></item><item><title>职业选择的考虑</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/posts/2011/10/career-choice-consideration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="257" height="33" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.xiami.com/widget/0_2960195/singlePlayer.swf" wmode="transparent"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以为自己N年前就写过这篇文章了，在网站上遍寻不获，为方便转发，只好重新码字。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在考虑换工作或者职业发展的下一步时，通常有这么几大因素需要考虑：老板，行业，地点，公司，职位，工作（工作环境，同事，交通，薪水，新技能。。。这些技术细节不是本文关注的焦点），按照重要性从高到低的排序如下：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;老板&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是最关键的因素，其重要性超过其他五项总和。跟对了人，其他所有问题都只是暂时的问题，都可以最终解决；跟错了人，则会陷入万丈深渊无法自拔。老板招人，但我们也在寻找最欣赏自己的伯乐，这个选择是双向的。人跟人之间的沟通很微妙，跟一个知己之间产生的化学作用可遇而不可求。遇上一个了解自己潜能，欣赏自己个性的老板，是万金难买的RP大爆发事件，要好好珍惜。在中国，这个因素尤其至关重要。一个好的老板，Ta的资源是跨行业跨地域的，可以带来无尽的新机会。在美国，这个因素的重要性稍微降低一些，因为美国地域太广阔（不像中国，大部分资源都集中在北京和上海），行业分化程度高，会削弱一个超级老板的影响力（但仍然是六项之首）。当目前的工作出现迷雾和不确定因素时，先看看老板的意向，看看你的下一步会对Ta产生什么样的影响，会帮助Ta解决什么样的问题，不要天真地一味从自己的利益角度出发考虑问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;行业&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;女怕嫁错郎，男怕入错行，这句话是公理。一个人的履历价值主要体现在两方面：行业经验/domain
expertise和功能技术/functional skills. 要达到行业顶端，domain
expertise是必要条件；到达了一个垂直行业的顶端后，可以凭借functional
skill进行跨行业的移动。Domain
expertise是靠一个工作一个工作积累起来的，频繁转行是大忌，青春时光只有二十年，也就经得起折腾个四五次，龟兔赛跑的道理浅显但常常被人遗忘。只有很少数的幸运儿在大学一毕业就能找到自己终身喜欢从事的事情，大多数人都需要经历几次行业的转变才会发现真爱。寻找自己热爱的事业，是一个更加宏大的终极命题，改日另行详述。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;地点&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个人三十岁以后的走势，社会关系是其主要推动力，而社会关系有极强的地域性。每次更换生活城市，所有的社会关系都得更新一遍，代价太大了。生活地点一旦定下来，买房，买车，都是迟早的规定动作，否则周围的人知道你是个浮萍，是个匆匆过客，不会在你身上投资过多的时间成本。对于想要回国的海外游子们，如果最终目的地是国内，则晚回不如早回。早一天回来，早一天开始积累人脉资源，没有其他捷径。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;公司&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;。。。没什么好说的，除了：行业比公司重要，公司跟职位之间的排序可以更换，但大多数时候公司比职位更重要，因为，公司比职位实在。很多时候，不同行业，不同公司里的看起来貌似相同的职业难以作比较，但公司之间是可以在品牌，美誉，规模上产生直接对比关系的。公司的存在感要比职位强烈得多。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;职位&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;职位的描述比较虚，表面上看不出来有什么不一样的地方，只有做了才知道，所以它的重要性也比较靠后。在很多行业里，有一些大家都公认的职位，这些职位的虚名可能比实际的工作性质更加重要。你要么做过，要么没做过，很多人就是凭照你的职位来定义你的能力。这虽然不是一个很公平的判断方法，但实际情况往往就是如此。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;工作&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;排名最后的，是你实际在做什么。这个因素调整起来相对比较容易，属于转变成本最低的。很多人的眼睛里就只盯着这个最浅显表象的因素，实在是本末倒置。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 15:47:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2011-10-21:posts/2011/10/career-choice-consideration/</guid><category>中文</category><category>theory</category></item><item><title>世说新语</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/posts/2010/06/real-meaning-of-English/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;这方面的书已经是汗牛充栋了，我也来凑凑热闹。以下是一些个人在公司里的感受。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a very good point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shit you just caught me off guard with my pants down!/I totally
missed that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's do a deep dive into this area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show me all the spreadsheets with the most gory details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me go socialize Tom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let me talk to Tom and try to get his buy-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the MAN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks for the Starbucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey I'm getting some Starbucks...you want anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I legitimately kiss you up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(responded from above) Yeah ... actually... I'll go with you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to talk to you in private. Got some rumors/gossips to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a good/bad guy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it favorable/unfavorable to net income?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah I hear you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand your concern and ... dear, I don't give a damn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretch line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;difference between my bottom-up forecast and the top-down requirement
on net income which I have no clue whatsoever how to achieve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go figure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know how to do it and I don't care. Just do it. That's YOUR
job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oops how come I missed that / Yeah right ... big deal ... so what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah...right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gotta be kidding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be a bad idea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This idea sucks. You can't think of anything remotely intelligent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just want to plant some seeds here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give this idea some thought, though it's still too early to talk about
it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just thinking out loud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have this brilliant idea and you have to hear it... you may not
understand it though and it may not have anything to do with the debate
here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just throw it to the wall and see what sticks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we do this to them, they will get hurt, but I don't care. Do it.
Only worry about it when they respond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the shit hits the fan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When this whole thing blows up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start FYIing stuff to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start putting my name in the "cc" field and do not expect me to do any
action, though I might.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just between us girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is just between you and me. It's totally unofficial and private.
(only used on guys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just want to make sure we are all on the same page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You so have no clue what this project is about. Let me explain it to
you, stupid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's just put some stakes in the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know whether this action is right or wrong, but we have to do
something, now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently he's been prepped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somebody already briefed him of the agenda before he came to the
meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just want to throw it out there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know whether this works or not and I take no stand on this
issue, but it's worth a discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just hear me out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know you disagree, but heck let me finish my freaking sentence!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we just have to agree to disagree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I acknowledge we've tried to resolve the dispute and we remain
divided, but it's ok. Our disagreement is not a show-stopper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, fine... let's talk about the process and policy then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are probably right on this one, but did you spell it out in the
standard operating procedure 152 section 47 paragraph 13? If not, I'll
do it my way. Go change the policy before picking up another fight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might want to have a closed-door conversation with Tom prior to the
meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure Tom is totally silent and nods to whatever we say on the
meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't mind being a good soldier if this is the moment of
all-hands-on-deck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't agree and don't want to do this. But if you order me to do so
and this is going to help you, fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the moment of all-hands-on-deck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company is in trouble... EVERYONE has to contribute. Otherwise we
all go down the drain together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 01:53:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2010-06-29:posts/2010/06/real-meaning-of-English/</guid><category>中文</category></item><item><title>Break Up GE To Unlock Its Value</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/posts/2006/05/break-up-GE-to-unlock-its-value/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;GE’s stock has been in a &lt;em&gt;5-year slump&lt;/em&gt; since 2001. Immelt’s got a tough job. He’s been relentlessly doing everything humanely possible to make the same GE sales pitch to analysts, major shareholders, the board, customers, employees, Dave Calhoun and himself. Fortune’s November issue runs a cover story on him and the photo displays his now completely-turned-silver hair. I recall his hair was mostly black when I saw him in Tokyo in mid–2001. Despite the best efforts from one of the best CEOs working today, investors are through buying it. GE stock is still going nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean while a noticeable &lt;em&gt;exodus&lt;/em&gt; is taking place with some of GE’s brightest executives. Cerberus Capital Management, the all-mighty hedge fund that trumped KKR in the then-landmark GMAC deal, has become a hub for GE alumni. GE managers, some of who report directly to Immelt’s staff (which means they have a legitimate shot at being CEO/CFO for many Fortune 500 companies, except for the top 20) , are quickly populating the ranks of various private equity and hedge fund firms. The exodus
reached alarming level when Dave Calhoun, a 27-year GE lifer who was once a front-runner in the horse race to succeed Jack Welch and now a vice chairman of the company, quitted in Aug 2006 to run a far smaller private media company VNU (backed by KKR, Blackstone and Carlyle), with a rumored $100MM potential incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been talked about the benefits of turning a company into a &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; one. The advantages are especially pronounced given today’s corporate governance activism (whether an ordinary man in the street agrees or not, some managers ARE worth hundreds of million dollars in
pay, not to mention private jet or Manhattan apartments) and Sarbanes Oxley Act. So my initial thought on how to salvage GE was on this path - what if we can LBO GE…? Well I quickly dismissed that myself. Indeed PE and Hedge Funds (the line to distinguish the two is fairly blur right now) are calling the shots all around, evidenced by the fact that the record for highest LBO deal has been set TWICE already in 2006, eclipsing the heyday of the greedy 80’s (on a side note, Lous Gestner - then in RJR Nabisco, is now back in the game with Carlyle, completing a full circle). Now they’re setting their eyes on Dell ($60BN) and Ford ($35BN). Only sky is the limit for those cowboys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However GE with $362BN market cap is clearly too much for &lt;em&gt;PE firms&lt;/em&gt; to make a run at. Besides the obvious financial hurdle, the current LBO model doesn’t fit for companies like GE or Apple. Among all others, the biggest change LBO brings to a public firm is that it puts a time stamp on the life of the company, which is otherwise presumed to exist in perpetuity. Live if you can make a change within the next five years; die if you can’t. That new corporate goal changes the entire mentality and easily solves the century-old agency problem. It makes a lot of sense if the company in its past life as a public entity is just an also-run. What if you’re already the market leader? What if your existence serves a higher purpose for the society at large, and for the sake for preserving mankind dignity your existence should be expected and allowed to last in perpetuity (Apple is an example; GE, hmm...arguably so)? Businesses of that nature probably won’t appreciate the short-term focus of PE firms, but ironically the structural advantages that PE firms can bring about are exactly what such businesses need so that they can: 1) focus on actually delivering the best products and services instead of utilizing management’s intellectual prowess in strategizing how to hit the EPS; 2) stop trying to figure out how to allocate income “stretch” targets; 3) leave the explanation of options backdating to accountants only; 4) forget about balancing double-digit growth in revenue, income, cash simultaneously while maintaining 20% ROE, which is a more formidable feat than proving Poincare Conjecture (go Perelman!); 5) sit down, have a cigar, and think about what is the next big thing that will reshape the planet and mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough said. So which model would fit GE? &lt;em&gt;Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/em&gt;’s is pretty close. Buffett essentially runs that as a private company - no meeting with street analysts, no earning forecast (if you don’t manage net income, how can you forecast? And then everyone says managing income is evil…duh?), no excessive sales pitch other than Buffett’s legendary annual letters. That culture is what GE needs to liberate its highly competent management team from numerous mundane short-term tasks and allow them to develop truly long-term vision and strategy for the company. Nonetheless, GE has another unique, insurmountable challenge - its size. Berkshire Hathaway has  $160BN market cap and GE’s more than twice of that. GE’s market cap has become so large and its business is
so diversified (the bite for being the all-time champion for diversification), it’ll just take too much market movement to nudge itsstock price. Unless GE has a true blockbuster product (like the light
bulb a century ago), investors can hardly get excited about its
performance (some washing machine and x-ray machines every now and then
ain’t enough). Over the years the giant company has turned into a
process-driven business rather than product/service-driven one.
Everybody knows GE will methodically meet its every target and continue
to churn out excellent managers, but few know GE Capital alone can rival
Citi Group, Bank of America and J.P. Morgan Chase in size and product
offering. GE is paying the price for its own size - its far-ranging
products and services are all excellent in their own right and market
segments, but they are trivialized when everything is added up to form
the sum of GE. There is a ton of value within each GE division it almost
seems that the entropy is lost or just cancelled out with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore IMHO the best way to unlock GE’s value is to &lt;em&gt;break it up&lt;/em&gt;. It
can be split into six businesses - Commercial Finance, Consumer Finance,
Infrastructure, Healthcare, Industrial and transportation. It’s not
exactly a clean-cut but it’s doable. Some of those P&amp;amp;Ls will be innerly
harmonized enough to form their own identity, culture and mission to go
to greatness on their own. Some of them may be more challenged with an
identity crisis, but they will survive. GE’s portfolio model (used to be
callled SBU.. Anyone still remember?) has been extremely successful in
the past, and to this date is still the envy for many other companies.
It has four major advantages, but I’ll argue none of them should be a
show-stopper to break up GE. GE’s old model has four distinctive
features. In today’s world, either they’re no longer valid, or they’re
no longer part of cost of living to stay in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Human Resource Training&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People is the best product coming out of GE. Millions of young, ambitious professionals flock to GE’s leadership training programs for their assortment of business and management training that is unparalleled in the world, both in breadth and depth. Once you’re marked as an “A” player, you’re expected to move to a new location, join another division, take new role and responsibilities every 18 to 24 months (yeah your kids will be multi-lingual, cross-culturally attuned
by birth right). However, given GE’s siiiiiiiize, even after break-up,
the new baby-GEs will still have enough critical mass to provide
training opportunities in almost the same magnitude. All of them are
already bona fide global platforms. In addition, people start domain
specialization fairly soon within 2–3 years after they join the company.
If I started out with NBC at Rockefeller Center, would I really want to
accelerate my career in Cincinnati in GE Transportation (big plant
there)? Well, I’m sure I can find equally appealing placement elsewhere
in NBC Universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Capital Allocation / the science of levering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic mojo for GE that once dazzled many competitors.Some businesses like GE Industrial are cash cows that don’t make too much net income but generate cash consistently. GE consolidates that cash (the treasury operation is a wonder to behold) and throw that around in high-growth businesses to make acquisitions. It’s a very efficient use of capital and only possible when you have a mix of industrial/capital and “cash cow”/“star” businesses. I would very much like to indulge in a more detailed discussion of “levering” for people who still recall the basic corporate finance principles from Brealey and Myers, but I should probably stop right here since I’m not entirely sure such levering mechanism is public knowledge. Mr. Bill Gross from Pimco almost stepped on this in his 2002 crusade on GE. Long story short, GE recapitalized quickly in response to Gross’ assault, and that discretion on capital allocation among its myriad of businesses is now gone (there are other benefits of NOT doing that though). Also, there is so much liquidity in the market now - GE is no longer the privileged few who can amass large sum of capital on a minute’s notice (just think about Blackstone’s $20BN fund). This paragraph may have unintended gaps in logical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portfolio Diversification&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old topic with a new twist in the age of ultra rapid value creation.
Business 101 says that diversification is useless (“home-made” effect),
and in fine print below it also says that “… except for GE”. GE has been
the consummate poster-boy defending the value of diversification. It’s a
simple premise: its 1,000+ businesses are all in different industry
cycles; at any given point, some will do well and some will not. The
good and bad cancel out each other and usually what is left is gravy. It
is a good, almost risk-free strategy, but not a particularly exciting
one. Andy Grove says “Only the Paranoid Survive” (btw, that book doesn’t
offer that much insight really. The old man is repeating himself too
much), I say " Only the Double-Down Survive“. GE’s diversification has
created a false sense of safety. 10% year-over-year steady growth may
suffice in the past 100 years, but it’s not going to cut it in the new
century when a garage business of 40 people can create  $1.6BN over 18
months. On the other hand, GE Capital raised many eyebrows when it
quietly started dominating GE’s balance sheet and profit and loss
statement left and right. Indeed, if every soul on the street looks at
GE as a finance company, GE will have to carry the same inspiring PE
ratio as those financial firms - not a pretty outlook (but in a way it’s
already happening). Therefore GE has to”balance" its Capital business
growth with that of its Industrial business. I say, if GE Capital can
grow 30% a year, let it roll and maybe that’ll be more than enough to
make up for a lower PE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One Corporate Brand Image&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another argument for one GE lies in the brand name of GE. This is a
touchy subject and I hold tremendous pride for this name. However I
would tentatively toy around some timid thoughts that may suggest GE’s
size is approaching to a level that could diminish its image and brand
recognition. If one think about “What is GE?”, an old tag line emerges
“Bring Good Things to Life”. True, GE used to exist for betterment of
mankind in general, and it actually carried out that mission fairly
well. What does it mean today? With all the breakthroughs in consumer
technology and unprecedented business models, it doesn’t mean a whole
lot. GE has way too many products and services for average consumer to
make out a sketch of what it really is. It’s not like
Apple=Innovation+Cool, or Walmart=Evil Empire/The Only Mall That Matters
For Your Neighbourhood, or Google=Wonder Boy Wandering in Wonderland.
Regardless of whether those images are good or bad, they are engraved in
people’s minds and investors can easily relate to them. Immelt saw the
statement become a bit staled and hollow. He made a sweeping change in
2005, opting for “Imagination at Work”. Immelt is smart. He certainly
felt the coming of an identity crisis. Do people really buy that? Only
time will tell but I can at least argue that the inclusion of certain
businesses do not necessarily inspire aura of “imagination” for average
Joe. If GE were broken up into a few pieces, the new baby-GEs will be
more recognizable with potentially more coherent messages to convey to
their respective targeted customer segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round up my 20 cents, going private will give GE much needed
structural and process advantages to let it focus on running the
business. Today’s PE models and Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway model
provide bits of the elements that will be helpful to GE, but the
transition from current GE to those models is beyond the capacity and
technology of today’s financial market (we need another Michael Milken).
A detour that may get GE there and fully unlock GE’s value seems to be
breaking it up into a few baby-GEs. It’s an audacious thought that
challenges several conventional wisdoms built around GE’s success to
date, but in today’s changed environment, those words of wisdom are in
need for new validation and interpretation anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does that make any sense to you … no?&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2006 23:05:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2006-05-09:posts/2006/05/break-up-GE-to-unlock-its-value/</guid><category></category></item></channel></rss>