<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/category/.framework.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 08:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Information Discovery Process of Travel</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/info-discovery-of-travel/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Many of my friends including myself have contemplated creating new business models in the travel space over the years. This is an interesting area that resonates with many people's personal experiences and something that almost everyone can relate to. We often feel there is something missing here or there, and it's not easy to articulate exactly where and what. Travel business, unlike movie and other business, is very hard to determine what is the basic element for a single data entry point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of a database (which is the backbone of every Internet business), if the data point cannot be universally defined and understood, then there is no database to speak of and no business to be built upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For movies, it's easy - every movie or TV episode is uniquely identifiable on IMDB.com and everybody agrees that's how they should be indexed in the database. Likewise for books, every book has an ISBN number that makes it uniquely identifiable, which lays down the foundation of Amazon's early success. For music, it's a bit tricky - we can index music by artist, song or album. Among these three elements, only artist can be easily indexed. Albums is becoming increasingly irrelevant (which is sad). Songs, unfortunately, can have multiple versions (studio, live, bootleg) that adds layers of complexity to all the music Internet startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case for travel is confusing at best. Should we define the basic data point as a destination (Yosemite National Park), a location (California), an attraction (Half Dome), a route (Pacific Highway 1), a photo album (Flickr), a travel package (Expedia), or some sort of hybrid? All seem to be fair games. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A random conversation with a friend who was en route to Yosemite prompted me to sort out the information discovery process of a typical traveler in a logical sequence, with specific objectives and needed information for each stage. The right-most column in the below table lays out the source of information at each stage, which is essentially the landscape of the travel industry as we know today. I call this "&lt;strong&gt;AESPA&lt;/strong&gt;" framework. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Stage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Main Questions&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Info Needed&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Source of Information&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; - Aware&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;What are the possible destinations?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;List of recommendations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;media, friends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt; - Excite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Which one looks most exciting?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Images to arouse interest; Reasons for must-go&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Herbert's Guide to ...&lt;/em&gt;; Google Image Search&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt; - Select&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Are there any show stoppers?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seasons of tourism; Visa requirement; Safe issues; Physical requirement; Advanced reservation; Cost&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Official sites; Wikipedia; fragmented info on Internet&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt; - Plan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How to make it happen?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Transportation; Accommodation; Ticketing; Itinerary; Budget&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Expedia; Kayak; TripAdvisor; Airbnb; Lonely Planet; Frommer's Guide; Fodor's Guide; Ticketmaster; Blogs of walkthroughs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; - Anticipation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;How to make the most out of it?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stop-by-stop details; restaurants and bars; Knowledge of history and culture&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Books; Yelp; TripAdvisor; Wikipedia; Flickr photos; Pinterest; Instagram&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Herbert's Guide to ...&lt;/em&gt; will serve the needs for the second stage "E" to excite travelers, arouse interest and build conviction that this is a must-go destination. My guide has a few features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All from my personal experience. I only write about places I have been to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All represent my recommendation. I only write about things that I think worth my friends' consideration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each guide will contain no more than 10 photos. I don't think any human being today has attention span for any photo album of more than 10 images unless it's from a family member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each guide will have a google map marked with all the recommended attractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guides will not contain lengthy walkthroughs with many logistic details/reviews/advice, which are for stage "P" and "A". I wish I could do that but always found I could never afford that much time to complete a full walkthrough. Thus, I just do what I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, every photo was taken by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To all my friends who are thinking about starting a business in travel space, may this serve as a sparkle to stimulate additional thoughts and inspirations.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-05-31:info-discovery-of-travel/</guid><category></category></item><item><title>COASSF#61 - What Do You Want to Get in Stanford - PFIKER Model</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/goals-in-stanford/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When I look back at the past year in Stanford/GSB/Sloan Fellow Program
and reflect what was it that we tried to get out of this incredible
experience, I think our goals fall into six mutually exclusive and
collective exhaustive categories, namely, &lt;strong&gt;PFIKER&lt;/strong&gt;. It is important
for us to know what our goals are, from Day One into the community, so
that we can strategize priorities, plan our academic and social life
accordingly, to get the most out of our time in Stanford. 12 months go
by really, really fast. Without clear goals in mind, it's easy to let
the time and opportunities slip through our fingers before we know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Goals.png", width="800px" alt="Goals in Stanford"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;artner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking for partners, in business or in life. For
business partners, spend more time with alumni, in study groups, social
gatherings and pay attention to those who tend to take initiatives/run
for class officers. Take one of the four major startup-themed classes to
interact with students from Computer Science (CS) and Engineering, who
are the real movers and shakers of the Silicon Valley. For life
partners, spend more time with MBAs starting from the Autumn Quarter.
It's ok to date another Sloan, but it might get tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F&lt;/strong&gt;riend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking for new friends, from new cultures, from new
industries, from new interest areas. Regularly hang out in the Sloan
Study Rooms ("Slounge") and make sure leave the door open, attend all
the TGIFs, join all the study trips (the Seatle one, the East Coast one,
and the self-organized international one), and take the initiatives to
organize small-party dinners (six person is the ideal size). Running for
social chairs will also help you make friends quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nspiration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking for inspirations that connect dots, bridge
isolated domains of knowledge, expand our horizon, or provide that
"eureka" moments. Attend &lt;a href="http://etl.stanford.edu/"&gt;Wednesday's ETL&lt;/a&gt; in
Engineering School religiously, attend as many seminars, talks, BBLs in
and around GSB as possible. Take some classes outside of GSB. Attend
industry conferences around Silicon Valley by taking advantages of
student discounts. Read the blog by &lt;a href="http://sten.tamkivi.com/"&gt;Sten&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/"&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K&lt;/strong&gt;nowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking for knowledge, things that we have never been
exposed to in prior jobs. Max out the cap level of 22 credits
Autumn/Winter/Spring and audit as many classes as schedule allows. If
your Sloan classmates can still remember your name by Spring Quarter,
you should consider yourself a big failure in this regard - OK.. that's
a bad joke. The point is that if you're so academically inclined, you
can never study hard enough and Stanford has enough interesting courses
to keep you intellectually stimulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;xperience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking for the quintessential "Stanford" experience and
try to experience as many actions as possible that Stanford can offer.
Run for a class officer role - whatever it is, as long as it helps to
serve the Sloan class and GSB community. Attend all the sports events in
the summer and the autumn (the football season is only in the
summer-autumn quarter I think). Take some physical exercise classes in
Winter and Spring Quarter, like golfing, horse-riding, yoga, or
swimming. Join some student's clubs. Participate in a flash mob if
someone in your class has the balls and guts to actually organize that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eputation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of us are looking to establish a personal brand that people can
remember us by. I think the importance of reputation cannot be
overstated. However it seems to have been ignored by many. GSB
(including 80+ Sloans and around 800 MBAs) is a very competitive
environment (duh....) and Sloans have only one year to leave our marks.
If you don't do something to put your name out there, people will not
remember you - plain and simple, and you don't want people at the end of
day to comment you along the lines of "yeah, he's a really nice guy...".
There are just too many overachievers around the campus in all
disciplines. Since you've already made it all the way up here, you might
as well just try a bit harder to get more mileage out of this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the top 3 priorities are Inspiration, Reputation, and Partner.
That pretty much explains why and why not I did certain things when in
Stanford, for whoever is curious about it. I come from a very heavy
business/finance background with extensive global trails and mix of
corporate/startup experience. Not too many courses in GSB are completely
new to me, nor do I really want to refresh my memory in Accounting,
Economics, or Statistics. So I tried to minimize my study load and free
up myself to do other things. I've lived in too many countries before to
care about checking all the boxes to make sure I've "been there, done
that", not to mention I&lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/why-here-why-now-why-again/"&gt;was planning to settle down in the Bay
area&lt;/a&gt; even before I
came to Stanford.  Why Inspiration, Reputation, and Partner? &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_35_my-bbl/"&gt;My
BBL&lt;/a&gt;
has explained it all. Now it feels like a full circle is completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carpe diem!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-07-05:goals-in-stanford/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#56 - How To Make A Star</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/how-to-make-a-star/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From a recent project in my favorite course of the quarter: OB388
Leadership in Entertainment Business, my group researched and analyzed
the success of K-Pop. During this exhilarating intellectual process, I
came up with this graph that illustrates how to find the optimal path of
nurturing a star from scratch. The horizontal dimension, from low to
high, represents the technical difficulty of acquiring certain skills
(which are also the cultural products those stars will eventually
produce) for a star in an entertainment business. The vertical
dimension, from low to high, represents  the cultural barrier those
cultural products will encounter when they are delivered to a foreign
culture (like from South Korea to America).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Star-Making.png" width="800px" alt="How to make a star"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why for K-Pop stars, they all start with dancing and singing.
It's called Audiovisuality. It gets more difficult after that.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 17:01:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-06-05:how-to-make-a-star/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>Drivers of Your Life - SIMPLERK</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/drivers-of-your-life/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The honor of the soundtrack for this article goes to the iconic and haunting monologue by Ewan McGregor in "Trainspotting"(1996) that defined the 90s, together with that "You Never Can Tell" dance in "Pulp Fiction"(1994). The full "choose life ... " monologue starts at 02:38.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.xiami.com/widget/0_2547984/singlePlayer.swf" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="257" height="33" wmode="transparent"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2007 I had tried out every career assessment tool or personality test
there was in the market.   Those tests were helpful to some extent, but
the overall value was limited, at least for me. Unsatisfied with what
was available, I started developing a more effective
framework/methodology to find out the key drivers that may explain why I
like doing certain things more than others and figure out what would be
my best career choice given what I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time I was &lt;a href="../../../2007/08/leaving-GE/"&gt;on my way out of General Electric
(GE)&lt;/a&gt;. GE taught
me everything I knew and I was eternally grateful for an exceptionally
enriching professional experience it had bestowed me with. However I
found myself gradually leaning toward a direction that would obviously
deviate from the trajectory that GE had always designed for me. I was
looking for my true self and didn't want to just fall into a pre-defined
category that others presumed I belonged to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quest for the ultimate answer to this ultimate question seems like a
universal one (unfortunately, the answer is not as easy as ... 42).
 Many of my friends all over the world are searching for it, and many of
my classmates in &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/programs/msx/"&gt;Stanford Sloan
Fellow&lt;/a&gt; master program are also
searching for it. As we walk through 30s, the most productive years of
our life, having bounced around several career tracks in the past, many
of us were taking a pulse asking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I really enjoy my current job?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the right career for me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should I really pursue in my life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would not be respectful to address these questions without mentioning
the monumental theoretical work by Maslow, who proposed his landmark
paper in 1943 "A Theory of Human Motivation". The famous "&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow's_hierarchy_of_needs"&gt;Maslow's
Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;",
which depicts hierarchy of needs, is well known. I got a taste of that
from the Social-Psychology class in my undergraduate days in &lt;a href="http://nus.edu.sg/"&gt;National
University of Singapore&lt;/a&gt;. The five layers of human
motivations, Physiological-Safety-Love/Belonging-Esteem-Self
Actualization, are probably the most widely quoted framework on this
subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all due respect to Maslow, I didn't feel his pyramid was sufficient
to explain drivers at deeper levels. His five layers are perfectly
correct, and do a good job explaining social behaviors by different
social classes in the same country or across different countries, but
that's not the area where most of my peers are struggling. Most people
who actually can afford the luxury to contemplate this question, are
struggling with drivers/motivations embedded in the top
"Self-Actualization" layer, which warrants a much more in-depth
analysis. We have to peel the onion even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another often-mentioned deep question is &lt;em&gt;What Gives You Happiness&lt;/em&gt;.
 Harvard's insanely popular course Psychology 1504 "Positive Psychology"
(aka, the "Happiness Course") has made a name for itself since 2006.
However I feel it's still left much to be answered. The question on
Happiness is not the same as the question on What Drives You to Do
Certain Things. Health, family time, California sunshine, these are the
obvious answers to Happiness and no one can dispute them - which means
they are not really particularly useful in solving our puzzle. In a very
tacky sense, we need to find out the fundamental drivers that make us
choose certain careers over others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, while I’m at it, I would define happiness as a kind of
sensation that you can derive totally independent from any
externalities. This simple and beautiful definition leads to many
implications, such as that money does not give you happiness (because
money is an externality), or that only spiritual enlightenment can bring
out true happiness, etc. Another definition I sometimes use, in a joking
fashion, is Happiness = Capability / Desire, which is pretty neat and
conveniently incorporates psychological expectation. Anyway, the
question of happiness is a different discussion all together. Let’s move
on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I don't think discussing &lt;em&gt;How To Be Successful&lt;/em&gt; is of much help.
Success is an over-rated and excessively discussed topic. Most people
tend to associate success with money, fame, achievement and getting up
on social ladder. People from different classes and cultures have vastly
different views on success and thus most discussions on success have
very limited mileage. To me success is to have the freedom to do what
one wants to without feeling constrained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the same token, I don't think this topic should be mixed with &lt;em&gt;What
Is Your Passion&lt;/em&gt;. Passion is closest to Driver, but not quite the same.
Passion sometimes borderlines with interests and interests are not
necessarily the fundamental drivers at our deepest psychological level.
Passion implies that people have a strong urge to do certain things, and
I feel many people don't really have that in them. But everyone has some
drivers, even for those with no noticeable passion in anything. Passion
is an often over-rated concept, especially in b-schools. In those
successful entrepreneurs I’ve known or heard about, &lt;a href="../../../2013/03/key-to-startup-success/"&gt;patience,
perseverance, and
tenacity&lt;/a&gt;are
the three most important attributes. Having passion definitely helps,
but I don’t feel it’s a necessary condition of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in 2007 I developed a &lt;em&gt;SIMPLERK&lt;/em&gt; method to help myself address
these questions. I found it useful in providing me with a consistent
guiding principle when making major career decisions. The assessment on
myself in 2007 has since withheld the test of time and is still valid
today. Over the years I've applied the same method on many friends. I
think most if not all my friends have found it useful to some extent as
well. For some of them, &lt;em&gt;SIMPLERK&lt;/em&gt; also revealed something in them
that they did not realize before, which came as a surprise with mixed
feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's how I use my &lt;em&gt;SIMPLERK&lt;/em&gt; method to solve the puzzle, once and for
all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1.  Assumptions:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we are doing this evaluation, we can no longer change what we are, because we have already passed the formation years of our lives. What this analysis reveals, is what you are. Whether you like it or not, you'll have to live with it. There is no "right" or "wrong" driver. No driver is superior to others. Every driver is reasonable and legitimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of this evaluation is probably valid for approximately
    10-15 years, after which your priorities may change, depending on
    individual circumstance or life-changing events (like, winning a
    lottery or marrying up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The below drivers are collectively exhaustive and mutually
    exclusive, as you may have noticed in every other framework I've
    developed. In my opinion, a list is of little value unless it tries
    to be collectively exhaustive and mutually exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These drivers are at the most fundamental psychological level. For
    example, some people may say, I want to be creative. Being creative
    is not a fundamental driver. Why you want to be creative? Because
    you want to be recognized (R) as being a creative person, or you
    want to influence (I) people's lives in unique way, or you want to
    leave behind a legacy (L) that distinctively has your mark?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sexual dominance is excluded from this evaluation for the sake of
    analysis. Many social psychologists would probably argue that this
    particular driver overshadows everything else single-handedly, as
    the mission for any civilization ultimately is to reproduce itself,
    preserve the best genes and allocate limited resources to ensure the
    survival of the fittest. Let’s just leave that aside and for a
    second focus on something more platonic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2.  Drivers: (SIMPLERK)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;tability &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stability is a desire to maintain a state of stability, avoid
unpredictable, reduce variability in life, seek for a kind of serenity
or tranquility. Some people are excited by a bustling life with constant
changes and new ventures, but some other people would prefer to have
greater control of his/her life and deal with things with well-defined
protocols/methods. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many careers are good venues for Stability, such as government jobs,
large corporate jobs, doctors, administrative/staff function jobs,
school jobs, etc. They are by no means easier, but usually are fairly
stable and you can figure out the rope quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;nfluence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influence is a desire to influence others’ behaviors and thoughts, to
change how people view or perceive certain things, to create a belief or
vision that people would follow, to make people do things they would not
do otherwise in the absence of absolute power, to will an action that
would not take place otherwise, to call to an action that people would
respond to. Influence is different from Power (which will be explained
later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influence can be found in many career choices, such as entrepreneurship
(change the world for a better place/make a dent in the universe),
designing (architecture, fashion, industrial design), religion founder
(Buddha , Christian Rosenkreuz), rebel (Gandhi, Che) bearer of hope
(Gandalf, Lawrence of the Arabia), teaching, writing, journalism, media,
activist, and Dr. Phil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;oney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is a desire for … for lack of a better word, money. I understand
the mere appearance of this word in such a context will stir endless
debate and controversy, because people tend to believe that Money should
never be the end goal, rather it should be a means to the end, or a
derivative of the end. Most lecturers teaching startup/entrepreneurship
in B-schools would say you should never work for Money but your true
passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not my intention to get into any fruitless and pointless debate
about Money’s relationship to other more gloried goals/drivers in life. It is just pretty obvious that Money is a significant factor in making
career decisions. Some people care more, and some people care less, but
either way it is there. Why young people go to investment banking or
strategy consulting? Among other things that may be spiritually or
intellectually elevating, let’s face it - it’s Money. So Money has a
rightful place in my SIMPLERK framework. I have seen people whose
singular goal is to make as much money as they can, regardless of which
venture they choose. Having Money in the discussion makes the discussion
much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Careers that provide loads of money include investment banking, strategy
consulting, law firms, big-four accounting firms, medical doctors,
investment (highly dependent on how long you can stay in the game and
when do you leave the game), gangster, and pirate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;ower&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power is a desire to make others bent to your will, by leveraging either
your social position or organizational position. It is much stronger
than Influence. Influence can be achieved forcefully or indirectly, in
an amicable manner, and Power is usually achieved in a much more
confrontational, direct manner. While both Influence and Power will lead
to altered behaviors of the recipients, Power has the additional benefit
of feeling unconstrained. Power as a desire probably has the greatest
impact to mankind’s history. Dynasties fall, nations rise, civilizations
sustain, all these can be attributed to some extraordinary individuals
who have insatiable appetite for power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Careers that lead to Power are government officials
(senators/congressmen, President, Speaker of the House, mayors,
ministers), founding fathers, military officers, big-corporate jobs,
movie directors, spies, super heroes (Batman, Spider Man, X-Men), any
senior job in a highly hierarchical organization where people pay more
attention to title/ranking than the person him/herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;egacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legacy is a desire to leave something behind to the world, to build
something that will stand on its own beyond our physical life, to create
something that can be carried forward generation after generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who desire for Legacy often donate money to build schools
(Stanford), build NPO foundations to tackle issues that no government or
corporate can handle (Gates Foundation), create art museums/galleries
that provide enlightenment (Getty, Guggenheim), write novels (Romance of
Three Kingdoms), develop real-estates, build bridges/dams, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;xperience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experience is a desire to experience as many things/adventures in life
as possible, to carpe diem, to live one’s life to the fullest, to leave
no regret before leaving this world, to be able to claim “I’ve been there, done that”. A lot of people travel around the world, try out different jobs, make new girlfriends/boyfriends in each new country, always appreciate new thrills that come his/her way and never get tired of them. They seem to be drifters, moving from one thing to another, sometimes without apparent logical rationale. I find this desire much more common in the western cultures than in the eastern cultures (which are usually more utilitarian-driven).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jobs that provide rich experience (can be in terms of physical
environment, people interact with, or the contents itself) include
corporate auditors, corporate road warriors (who get rotated to a new
assignment every few years), certain government officials on rotation
assignment (elite squad or diplomat), missionary workers, event
management (wedding planner, travel agencies), restaurant critics,
sailors, bar owners/tenders, performance acts, groupies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;ecognition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recognition is a desire to be recognized by either peers/family members,
or people you know, or even people you don’t know. There are three
layers of recognition: 1) being appreciated as in possession of certain
skills; 2) being recognizable by having a personal brand that is
associated with certain positive image/perception; 3) being recognized
as better than many peers who are in the same business/profession, or as
simply the best, the most awesome one, the one. Recognition is in some
way connected to vanity, though vanity conveys much more negativity.
Recognition is also related to a strong desire to express one’s self.
(Though I think there might exist one category of special individuals
whose sole desire is just to express him/herself, regardless how that is
perceived/recognized by others. Gao Xingjian made that point in his
acceptance speech for 2000 Nobel Prize in Literature, echoing the voice
of George Orwell in his 1946 essay "Why I Write").&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Careers that provide Recognition include sales, traders, investment
professionals (Buffett, Schwartzman), artists (Van Gogh, Pollock), poets
(Pink Floyd, Dylan), rock n’ roll stars (Led Zeppelin), writers
(Murakami), directors (Kubrick), movie stars/actors (Tom Cruise),
super-models (Adriana Lima), professional athletes (Jordan, Bryant,
Maradona), talk-show hosts (Fallon, O’Brien), and Kardashian sisters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;K&lt;/strong&gt;nowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is a desire to explore the unknown world, to advance mankind’s
frontier of intellect and knowledge, to figure out the answer to the
ultimate question in the universe, to look for perfection and harmony
that usually bear no meaning to day-to-day life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with such desire and derive happiness from such accomplishment,
can be found in SETI scientists, researchers, professors, astronauts,
code-breakers, inventors (Tesla), theoretical mathematicians, string
theorists, and Stephen Wolfram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3.  Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of SIMPLERK is very simple. After fully understanding the
    definition of the eight drivers, identify a few that resonate with
    you most. &lt;em&gt;Choose a career that does the best job in fulfilling all
    your identified drivers at the same time&lt;/em&gt;. Such a career may not be
    within reach to you right away and it might take a few stepping
    stones to get to it, but at least you know what it is. Sometimes
    such career may not even exist. Then you will need to invent it and
    find a platform that can carry it. The best jobs that the ones you
    create for yourself anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried SIMPLERK on many friends who are also on the quest
    looking for their meaning of life. The exercise has produced a
    surprisingly large variety in answers, which is pretty intriguing
    (to find out what my friends truly want and see that they all have
    different drivers) and at the same time demonstrates the robustness
    of this framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empirically most people identify 2 – 4 drivers from the above list
    of 8. It suffices to say if there is only one driver the person is not
    thinking wide open enough; if there are more than 4 drivers then the
    person has not quite figured out what he/she really wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that what drives us has a lot to do with our family
    background, the environment in which we’re brought up, and the way
    our parents educate us when we are young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is actually one more step to facilitate the finding of the
    drivers. In 2007 I quitted GE to work on a website full-time on my
    own to develop an ajax-based interactive tool. The tool provided
    much-needed scientific rigor into this framework and sort of helped
    testers figure out the drivers subconsciously (borrowing some ideas
    from Myers-Briggs Test). In late 2007 I went back to Beijing to join
    a VC-funded company as its CFO and discontinued the development of
    the website. Not sure where the codes are now, nor do I really care.
    I’ve found having beer in a noisy dive bar turns out to be quite
    effective, as well. The best part of SIMPLERK, and the most fun
    part, lies in its delivery, discussion and comparing notes. This
    writing cannot do its justice in that regard, but it’s a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4.  Synthesis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For your reference, my main drivers, in descending order of
    significance, are: &lt;em&gt;Influence&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Recognition&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Money&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2007, I have been using this SIMPLERK framework as a compass
    to guide me through &lt;a href="../../../2013/03/an-entrepreneurs-manifesto-POOOUA-model/"&gt;every career
    transition&lt;/a&gt;,
    from a corporate career in GE to CFO in China, then to an
    entrepreneur in the Bay area after Stanford. It’s done a very
    effective and adequate job explaining my every move, and it also
    explains why I would not fancy a career in VC just yet. I’ll be
    happy to share some personal thoughts on this in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to complete this article.  The end of my Sloan
    days feels like a right moment to synthesize everything. Hopefully
    my friends feel the same and find some value in SIMPLERK as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything written so far is just a prelude. The fun part of the
conversation only comes when we start applying &lt;em&gt;SIMPLERK&lt;/em&gt; on ourselves
and people around us, or figures we've heard about (say, Bill Gates or
Mayor Bloomberg). You know where to find me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 02:59:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-05-09:drivers-of-your-life/</guid><category>career</category></item><item><title>COASSF#51 - An Entrepreneur's Manifesto</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/an-entrepreneurs-manifesto-POOOUA-model/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As I was burning midnight oil on my final assignment/personal essay for
S353, I finally could not help but laying out my entire career
transitions, in the past, present, and future, on a diagram - something
I've been thinking about doing for a long time but never got the chance
to complete. This diagram is built on a framework I developed a while
ago &lt;a href="../../../2011/10/career-choice-consideration/"&gt;《Consideration in Career
Transition》&lt;/a&gt;,
which was written in Chinese and I haven't got the chance to translate
into English (if you know of any free secretary service, please let me
know. I can certainly use one or two.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, there are six dimensions for any career transition (obviously,
any list I have, is by definition collectively exhaustive and mutually
exclusive, otherwise what's the point of developing a
framework/theory?). They are, in descending order of importance:
sponsor, location, domain, company, function, and rank. In short, they
are "&lt;strong&gt;POOOUA&lt;/strong&gt;”. In different career stages we all try to move toward
our ideal career, but it usually takes multiple steps to complete the
transition along all six dimensions and rarely do we get to the dream
job at one go. Below diagram illustrates what kind of transition I
completed at each turn of my career. It almost reads like a manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Career-Transition.png" alt="Career Transition" width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 14:48:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-14:an-entrepreneurs-manifesto-POOOUA-model/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#50 - Key To Startup Success_Reflection from S353</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/key-to-startup-success/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In my last post on this subject, I compared some &lt;a href="../../../2013/02/comparison-S353-and-G566-in-GSB/"&gt;similarities and
differences between S353 (Entrepreneurship: Formation of New
Business)  and G566 (Real-Life
Ethics)&lt;/a&gt;,
two of my favorite GSB courses. Today's S353 class presented the last
case in this series of 18 very different and interesting startup
stories. So after all the discussions, what kind of lessons can we draw
from them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before George and Jim give us a summary on Thursday, I just want to
share my own takeaways. I call them "&lt;strong&gt;PPT&lt;/strong&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/keytostartupsuccess.png", alt="key to Startup Success", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find these three qualities are not only exemplified throughout all the
18 S353 cases we have reviewed, but also demonstrated in all the startup
success stories that I personally know of, whether in US, Europe or
China. There are many other situational factors or circumstantial
strategies that were also instrumental to the success for those
founders, but in the grand scheme of all things those more "operational"
factors tend to wash out and become no more than a white noise in the
distribution of a seemingly random walk. What stand out in the end as
the true significant drivers and the common denominators of all, are
&lt;em&gt;Patience&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Perseverance&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Tenacity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's worth noting that Passion is not part of this by my account, which
might surprise some people. I think passion is definitely and obviously
a common attribute to many successful founders, and the value of passion
is that it brings tenacity. Many people have enough passion, but if that
cannot be translated into &lt;strong&gt;PPT&lt;/strong&gt;, the venture would still fail. On the
contrary, we've seen enough successful founders in S353 that don't
appear to have built their businesses with a particular passion for the
product/service/business model, but they got sufficient PPT to live
through the peaks and valleys and that's what gives their stories to an
eventual happy ending.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 15:59:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-12:key-to-startup-success/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#24 - Evaluate Courses with CIDRAE</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/evaluate-course-with-CIDRAE/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I've been thinking about evaluating each course I've taken in &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/sloan"&gt;Stanford
Sloan Program&lt;/a&gt; individually, but I'm
afraid that my often highly opinionated remarks would hurt some feelings
and doom my future career in the Silicon Valley. So I developed a
framework during today's less-than-eventful class, called &lt;strong&gt;CIDRAE,&lt;/strong&gt; to
express a more balanced and comprehensive critique for each course. My
idea was inspired from the group exercise project (the U Penn PhD
curriculum one) for a course in the Fall Quarter &lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=GSBGEN+239%3A+Sloan%3A+Executive+Communication+Strategies&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;GSBGEN239 Executive
Communication
Strategies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt;ontents Usefulness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How useful are the contents? How relevant are
they to me? Are they what I want to learn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;nstructor's Presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is the instructor inspiring? Is his
presentation creative, engaging, or conducive for learning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;D&lt;/em&gt;ynamics in Classroom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there usually a spirited discussion or debate among students in the class? Are students proactively sharing their views and experiences to enhance the overall learning for the class?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;eading Load&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How heavy is the reading material? Are they compulsory
or optional?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt;ssignment/Project Load&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How heavy is the work load from assignments
and projects (individual and group)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt;xam Pressure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How stressful is it to prepare for the exam? How
menacing does the exam look like? How much psychological pressure does
it impose on me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C, I, D more or less measure how much I get out of the course, and R, A,
E measure how much effort I need to put into the course. For every
course, I'll measure it under these six dimensions and assign a value
from 1 to 5. 5 is the highest extend, and 1 is the lowest extend. Also
it's worth noting that RAE reflects how I treat the course requirement,
rather than what is officially required by the syllabus. The entire
CIDRAE score is, therefore, highly idiosyncratic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;CID&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Sum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;C&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;D&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;RAE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Sum&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;R&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;A&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;E&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;CIDRAE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;CID&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;RAE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Index&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;...... to be continued in &lt;a href="../../../2012/10/summer-quarter-course-evaluation/"&gt;Summer Qtr Course Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:14:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-10-18:evaluate-course-with-CIDRAE/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#06 - Live Stanford Life to the Fullest</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/live-stanford-life-to-the-fullest/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Life in Stanford comes to us like a bullet train. Before we know it's
already two months into the program. For all the Sloans, it's unlikely
we will ever come back to universities in a lengthy classroom setting
again. How to make the most out of this 12-month campus life is the
overarching question for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7150/13826223073_65507cee90_c.jpg" width="800" height="351" alt="infinity1"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study Group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The least we can do is to make a few friends we can always fall back
    to in the 5-person study group&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some groups study together (reading textbooks/doing homework); some
    groups only meet for discussion. Whichever way is choose, don't
    overkill on doing the coursework. They're necessary to fulfill
    course requirement and internalize the new knowledge, but after a
    certain point you'll only see diminishing return. Most of the cases
    are pretty interesting and I can easily dive into them for ten hours
    without boring myself but that's probably not the reason why I came
    to Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sloan Class&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to make more friends in the class is to hang out in
    the GSB Sloan Lounge, and keep the door open (so far my observation
    is that most Sloans tend to keep the door closed). We are lucky to
    have this lounge area with 6-7 study rooms for Sloans' exclusive
    use. Make the best use of them while we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend TGIF (Thanks-God-It's-Friday). From a pure utilitarian
    perspective it has probably the highest benefit-to-cost ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend social events organized by your hard-working social chairs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run for Social Chairs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stanford Graduate School of Business&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GSB-wide BBLs(Brown Bag Lunch) could be a good venue to meet
    with the MBAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be two mixer events for the Sloans organized by the MBA
    Liaison Chairs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting from Fall Quarter, some classes will be a mixer of Sloans
    and MBAs, while some classes will be strictly for Sloans. Talk to
    Academic Operation to find out which classes will have MBAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join GSB student clubs. MBA is the main driving force behind all the
    GSB-wide clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run for MBA Liaison Chairs (2 position) if you're single.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stanford University&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many talks/seminars throughout the campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many house parties organized by each EV apartment. Our
    neighbors are students from other schools. Stanford has a beautiful
    campus and most students choose to live on campus. University of
    Chicago, Columbia, or Yale can never compete with Stanford in this
    area. After living in Cambridge, MA for four years, I think MIT and
    Harvard also pale in comparison to Stanford's campus community.
    Somehow I always miss the ice cream party of Hoskins Midrise. What a
    shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Play sports (like pick-up basketball games) in Ford Center
    or Arrillaga Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose courses from other schools like Engineering, Design or Law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://continuingstudies.stanford.edu"&gt;Stanford's Continued
    Studies&lt;/a&gt; offers amazing
    classes to the public (for a fee). Sloans can attend them for free.
    I wish I had 48 hours a day just so that I could attend those
    wonderful and fascinating courses (many are non-business-related).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main reason many students come to Stanford Sloan.
    &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com"&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; is striving and used by many
    local interest groups from technology start-ups to investments to
    karaoke parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://startupdigest.com"&gt;Startup Digest&lt;/a&gt; is the one everybody
    reads. Go subscribe it. It's free. Its daily email lists out all the
    events around the valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rekindle relationship with local friends, long-lost
    class/school-mates. In Beijing the startup circle is rather
    hierarchical. You need to be senior enough in the company
    (director/VP and above) to break into circles that matter. In the
    valley it appears to have a flatter pecking order. Many people are
    engineers/coders, but they can still be very well connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend &lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/events/"&gt;TechCrunch's Disrupt&lt;/a&gt; event.
    This is one of the biggest events in the valley with the most stellar
    line-up of speakers. Usually its ticket (for 4-5 day) goes for
    nearly \$3,000, but for students it has a discounted price of only
    \$300. Take advantage of this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 14:44:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-08-28:live-stanford-life-to-the-fullest/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#05 - Sloan Officer Analysis</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/chair-analysis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of every quarter, Sloans will elect various &lt;a href="https://mygsb.stanford.edu/sloan/student/sloan-class-officers"&gt;class
officers&lt;/a&gt;
(chairs). For these Sloans who are willing to sacrifice their study
hours and step up for the greater good of the class, the below analysis
might be helpful in their consideration. If I could make a 3D chart I
would add one more dimension for the variance, but we'll start with a
simple one for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7252/13826718863_b546de0883_c.jpg" width="800" height="541" alt="officer analysis"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Treasury&lt;/em&gt;: usually collect money from Sloans (not the other one) ...
hard to amuse people with that ... have to deal with a lot of
cash-settlements ... just like in a typical CFO job, if you do well,
people take it for granted without understanding what a challenging
effort the job entails; if you don't do well, people keep whining about
it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Academic&lt;/em&gt;: liaison between Sloans and teaching faculties ... collect
feedback and provide feedback to faculties ... not an easy job to walk
that balance and gain goodwill from both sides ... the perceived
correlation between efforts &amp;amp; results is not as obvious as in other
officers' jobs ... haven't run into any academic crisis yet so let's see
how this one goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Web&lt;/em&gt;: hard work as people always have a million IT issues ...
people's expectation on response time makes the job even more
challenging ... clear perceived correlation between efforts and outcome
so their hard work does bring substantial goodwill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social&lt;/em&gt;: tremendous amount of work ... very hard to balance needs
from the entire class with such diverse backgrounds and opinions ...
execution could be a significant challenge because of the large number
of people involved in those events ... luckily people do appreciate the
efforts (regardless of how good the actual outcome is) , not to mention
those efforts are very visible, so it still can be a very rewarding
experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;President&lt;/em&gt;: (almost like the Speaker of the House) as the agenda
setter for the class has considerable power to influence the
effectiveness/collaboration among the chairs and between students and
staff; not an easy job though as its deliverables are not as
clearly-defined as those for other officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yearbook&lt;/em&gt;: hardest of all ... because the monster effort only kicks
in at the end of the 12-month Sloan period as people are moving on to
other ventures and priorities ... almost feel like the last one to turn
off the light ... but no doubt people's happiness level will be raised
substantially when the yearbook comes off the printer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of variances or risks, I think Social, President and Yearbook
have bigger potential swings (it's either love or hate from the critical
and opinionated Sloans) ... and Web, Treasury, and Academic probably
have narrower confidence intervals.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 18:20:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-08-27:chair-analysis/</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>Can You as a CFO survive the journey of leading a pre-IPO company to IPO?</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/can-you-as-a-cfo-survive-the-journey-of-leading-a-pre-ipo-company-to-ipo/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;When you join a pre-IPO company as its CFO, the holy grail (well, for most) is to get this baby to IPO. It brings fame, exit money, and an enviable career achievement that will always give you a boardroom directorship for post-exit retirement life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This decision tree illustrates potential roadblocks along this journey and helps you figure if your set-up has all the right elements for your goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/IPO-tree.jpg" alt="IPO Survival Tree", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 14:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-02-24:can-you-as-a-cfo-survive-the-journey-of-leading-a-pre-ipo-company-to-ipo/</guid><category></category></item><item><title>跟你干革命，凭什么？</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/what-does-it-take-to-be-a-good-boss/</link><description>&lt;iframe width="257" height="33" src="http://www.xiami.com/widget/0_387736/singlePlayer.swf" wmode="transparent"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在江湖浮沉数载，从外企到国企到民企，历经各种叱咤风云的领袖人物，常考虑一个问题，作为老板（或者领导），你凭什么让人跟你干革命？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我总结了一下，大概有七种方式，简称&lt;strong&gt;PLORHIM&lt;/strong&gt;（普罗西姆）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;. 下属跟着你，觉得前途无量（&lt;em&gt;Prospect&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;: 下属跟着你，学（&lt;em&gt;Learn&lt;/em&gt;）到了东西（技能，经验，见识）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O&lt;/strong&gt;: 下属跟着你，得到很多权力和尝试的机会（&lt;em&gt;Opportunity&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;: 下属跟着你，觉得自己的价值得到了体现和认可（&lt;em&gt;Recognition&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;. 下属跟着你，觉得很开心（&lt;em&gt;Happiness&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: 下属跟着你，觉得从事了一项有意义的伟大事业（&lt;em&gt;Inspiration&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;: 下属跟着你，挣到了钱（&lt;em&gt;Money&lt;/em&gt;）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;老板们很难做到在七个方面都出类拔萃，而且也没有这个必要，但每个老板都有自己特别擅长的地方。GE的领袖们很难在&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;（只是略高于market rate而已），&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;（每个人都只是一架大机器里的螺丝钉，而这个大机器看起来性感程度有限），或者&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;（苦多乐少，工作强度太大了）上满足野心勃勃的年轻人，所以他们在&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;，&lt;em&gt;L&lt;/em&gt;，&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;上特别花功夫。GE的FMP（Financial Management Program）和CAS（Corporate Audit Staff）作为全世界最优秀的企业领袖培训项目在新人们刚加入公司时就赋予他们巨大的责任和环游全球的机会，是P，L，O的集中体现。至于R，那是GE的领袖们信手拈来的（could you get me a Starbucks? wow, you are the Man!）。公司用各种360 review, CEO lunch, Crotonville
classes，让年轻人时时热血沸腾，保持着超级赛亚人3的鸡血状态，&lt;em&gt;GLOR&lt;/em&gt;的完美结合是GE这家百年老店还能保持旺盛的战斗力和创新精神的根本来源。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在四大会计事务所和几大Strategy Consulting
Firms（譬如McKinsey和BCG）里，在前几年，可能&lt;em&gt;L&lt;/em&gt;和&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;的比例高些，&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;应该不错，因为团队人员平均素质都很高。跟高素质的人在一起总是一件让人身心愉悦的事情。&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;也还可以（起码他们自己这么认为），P当然还行，R得看具体老板，I就没什么可谈的了（会计事务所和Stra Consulting
Firm在商业社会里扮演着非常特定的角色，这个角色是必要的，但也不必过度神话）。到了合伙人级别，剩下的动力可能主要就是M了，其他的我觉得都很有限，个别龙凤级别的或许在P和O上还有潜力。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于微软的老板们，&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;是一个主要的武器。微软在市场上一直是支付着行业里几乎最高的薪水。&lt;em&gt;L&lt;/em&gt;应该也是微软值得称道的地方，起码在产品方面。他们的产品经理在市面上非常抢手。很多最大型的IT项目，只有微软这种现金多得没地方花的公司才会undertake，所以具备这种经验的IT人是难得的。I恐怕高不到哪里去（After all, they make, like.... Windows products...）。Gates之后，微软的话事人不幸成为IT界著名谐星Ballmer，屡败屡战，所以R就不用谈了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;总部在波士顿的某大型资产管理公司W，主要从&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;方面吸引人才。作为一家盛名卓著的老牌old
money firm，在L，I和R方面跟其他firm差别不大。M方面不错，但行业里的几家顶级基金都是这个价。W在&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;方面很下功夫，召集了一群非常聪明优秀的人在一起，给他们极大的自由度，想研究什么就研究什么，想去哪儿就去哪儿。对于一个高智商的人，最大的快慰就是跟一群同样高智商的人在一起朝夕相处，员工幸福指数居高不下。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;绝大部分的投行（或者说，所有的投行）主要在&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;方面满足员工，其他方面看个人造化了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于超级牛人譬如Jobs和马云，他们把&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;发挥到了极致；对于史玉柱，他对老人的&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;照顾得很不错（可能因为他们在I方面损失比较惨重吧）；对于红杉的沈南鹏，他把&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;抬得极高，同时刻意压低R；对于创新工场的李开复，他独辟蹊径，卖的是&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;；对于大多数创业型的小公司，主要卖的是&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;，老板层次高一点则可以在L和H上下文章。依此类推，不一而足。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从老板的角度，成本最低，最容易做到的是&lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;，只要稍微花点心思就可以让员工工作得比较开心。比H高一个层级就是&lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;，只要有正确的心态就可以很容易让员工感受到成就感和尊重。再往上就是&lt;em&gt;O&lt;/em&gt;，老板未必需要技压群英，只要给予下属足够的O，也能笼络人心。大多数老板或多或少都能在L方面让下属觉得跟得有点价值。P和I是最高层级的手段了，只有具备超越凡人的自信心和耀眼光环的牛人才玩得起。如果一个老板几乎一无是处，起码在&lt;em&gt;M&lt;/em&gt;方面别亏待了下属，很多时候光这个也就够了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个老板如果知道自己的短板，就应该在其他方面补足。如果Ta在这七个方面&lt;strong&gt;PLORHIM&lt;/strong&gt;都没有亮点，那么这种老板不跟也罢。证毕。&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 18:11:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2011-10-10:what-does-it-take-to-be-a-good-boss/</guid><category>中文</category></item></channel></rss>