<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/category/.stanford.rss" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:52:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>Buzz Words from Stanford GSB BLAST Mail</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/buzz-words-stanford-gsb-blast-mail</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This program aims to analyze the most common buzz words from Stanford
Graduate School of Business (GSB)'s BLAST mailing list, which is
subscribed by all GSB students (MBA, MSx and PhD) and used heavily by
the student community to broadcast news, seeking help, etc. The idea is
similar to Google Keyword Trend, except that it's applied to a very
specific environment and audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/buzzGSB.png" alt="Buzz Word from Stanford GSB" width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program is written in Python 2.7.5 and &lt;a href="https://github.com/zire/buzzInStanfordGSB"&gt;the source code is on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download all the BLAST emails&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately Google provides a very handy Datatool to download emails
with specific labels. It's available from the Account Settings page.
This archive has emails from 2012 (I recovered them from Trash), 2013,
and 2014. Emails in 2012 and 2013 were not preserved universally and
consistently so they will not be part of this analysis. Emails in 2014
are of better quality though I'm sure I've missed/deleted some BLAST
messages already. Going forward I will keep all the BLAST emails and the
data quality will be considerably better in more recent update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extract emails and dates from the email archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google archives Gmail messages in mbox format - one single large file.
Python's mailbox.mbox library provides an effective way to extract
contents from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;_mbox2csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;py&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are three steps that need to be performed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;figure out where is the email body with get_payload()&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that all the BLAST emails are of multipart (so get_payload() will return a list, not a string). The email body is hidden in the first part of the first part in a message from mbox (quite nested).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;clean up the date field&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The raw date field needs clean-up. It's not in the standard ISO format
and the day field is not zero-paddled. Datetime.strptime is used to deal
with it. Eventually a raw date like "5 Nov 2013" is converted into
"20131105" (YYYYMMDD) for easy sorting in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sort data by date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-explanatory. After this program is run, a cleaned up email archive
will be created in csv format with only date and email body information,
and is sorted by date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the word frequency analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;_wordcount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;py&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After all the maneuvers to get the data into the right format, the real
crunching on word frequency is quite easy relatively speaking. The true
magic that embodies both science and art is the exception list of words
to ignore (words_to_ignore). A lot of time was spent to grow this list
so that all the un-informational words are filtered out such as "when",
"where", "to".. etc. There are A LOT of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's only after filtering out those exception words, the real buzzwords
for Stanford GSB will float to the surface, as you can see from above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do they reveal something useful? Maybe, but I'm not sure. Maybe I just
need to continue to tinker with the exception word list to make more
sense out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:52:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-03-21:buzz-words-stanford-gsb-blast-mail</guid><category></category></item><item><title>Confession of a Stanford Sloan Fellow, A Summary</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/confession-stanford-sloan-fellow-summary</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This series ran for 62 episodes, taking notes and reflections during my
12 months in Stanford Graduate School of Business' Master of Science for
Experienced Leaders (MSx, aka, Sloan Fellow) program. The original
episodes were scattered around in my blog, together with photo series,
dance videos, rock band videos, and self-invented theoretical
frameworks. I didn't intend to put them in nice order because the
structure of this blog was meant to force readers to read every article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series is not finished yet. Despite of the various works I've done
during the Sloan year, I'm yet to unveil my most satisfactory and
ambitious project for my distinguished Sloan Class of 2013. Tentatively
I'll debut that on our ten year anniversary dinner and dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, everybody can use an index to navigate through this
journey up to today. Hence, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../survival-guide-for-the-first-three-days/"&gt;01_Survival Guide for the First Three
Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;02_How to Set Up Stanford Email on OSX
Mail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;03_How to Plan a Beach Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;04_Let’s Get It On&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../chair-analysis/"&gt;05_Sloan Officer Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../live-stanford-life-to-the-fullest/"&gt;06_Live Stanford Life to the Fullest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;07_Difficult Communication, A Revisit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;08_Phil Libin Talk (CEO of Evernote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;09_Stanford MBA vs Stanford Sloan Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10_Set Up Home Network in EV&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11_Social Chair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12_Set Up Sloan Program Calendar on iPhone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13_TechCrunch Disrupt SF Day 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14_Tribute to Mid-Autumn Festival&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15_Fall Quarter Courses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16_Elections 2012_Oct 02&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17_ETL Seminar_Oct 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../10-reflections-of-a-cfo/"&gt;18_10 Reflections of a CFO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19_Powerpoint &amp;amp; Business Plan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../dance-of-my-life/"&gt;20_Dance of My Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21_Demystify Board of Directors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22_New Spin on iShare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23_Geoff Yang’s Winning Entrepreneurs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../evaluate-course-with-CIDRAE/"&gt;24_Evaluate Courses with CIDRAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../summer-quarter-course-evaluation/"&gt;25_Summer Quarter Course Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26_Fall Quarter Course Evaluation (Interim)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27_Famous Speeches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28_Talk with Steve Blank and Andy Rachleff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29_Usefulness of Learning Various Accounting Concepts in B-School&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../view-from-california/"&gt;30_View from California&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../dummys-guide-to-business-plan/"&gt;31_A Dummy’s Guide to Business Plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../from-gsb-reporter/"&gt;32_GSB Reporter – Bubbles &amp;amp; Flash Mob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;33_A Fictional Debate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../application-to-dmedia/"&gt;34_Application to dMedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../gangnam-style-goes-to-stanford-ncaa-half-time-show/"&gt;Gangnam Style Goes to Stanford NCAA Half-Time Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../my-bbl/"&gt;35_My BBL, My Choices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../rock-band-debut/"&gt;36_Rock Band Debut of The Spillovers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../fall-qtr-course-evaluation/"&gt;37_Fall Quarter Course Final Evaluation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../sell-used-textbooks/"&gt;38_Sell Used Textbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../reflection-notes-from-s353-jan-15/"&gt;39_Reflection Notes from S353 Jan 15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../reflection-notes-from-s353-fitness-anywhere-case/"&gt;40_Reflection Notes from S353 Jan 17 Fitness Anywhere Case&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../why-search-funds-make-sense/"&gt;41_Why Search Funds Might Make Sense&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../15-things-to-know-in-strategizing-your-course-portfolio/"&gt;42_15 Things to Know in Strategizing Your Sloan Courses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../where-is-stanford-sloan-fellow/"&gt;43_Where Is Stanford Sloan Fellow?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../must-play-list-for-chinese-new-year-party/"&gt;44_Music Play List for Chinese New Year Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../should-you-do-stanfords-famous-startup-courses/"&gt;45_Should You Do Stanford’s Famous Startup Courses?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../comparison-S353-and-G566-in-GSB/"&gt;46_Comparison of S353 (Formation of New Venture) and G566 (Real-Life Ethics)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../sloan-fellow-life-cycle-how-to-make-the-most-out-of-it/"&gt;47_Sloan Fellow Life Cycle &amp;amp; How To Make The Most Out Of It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../my-yearbook-message-for-Stanford-Sloan/"&gt;48_My Yearbook Message&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../chinese-new-year-party/"&gt;49_Chinese New Year Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../key-to-startup-success/"&gt;50_Key To Startup Success_Reflection from S353&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../an-entrepreneurs-manifesto-POOOUA-model/"&gt;51_An Entrepreneur’s Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../stanford-business-magazine-quote/"&gt;52_Stanford Business Magazine Quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../10-things-to-do-before-coming-to-stanford-sloan-master-program/"&gt;53_10 Things To Do Before Coming to Stanford Sloan Master Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../rock-out-stanford-coho/"&gt;54_The Spillovers Live! at Stanford Coho Cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../stay-full-stay-smart/"&gt;55_GCBC Talk_Stay Full Stay Smart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../how-to-make-a-star/"&gt;56_How To Make A Star&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../swan-song-by-the-spillovers/"&gt;57_Swan Song by The Spillovers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../course-evaluation-winter-q/"&gt;58_Course Evaluation_Winter Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../course-evaluation-spring-Q/"&gt;59_Course Evaluation_Spring Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../april-orientation-performance-at-cemex-auditorium/"&gt;60_April Orientation Performance at CEMEX Auditorium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../goals-in-stanford/"&gt;61_What Do You Want to Get in Stanford_PFIKER Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../Herbert-GCBC-Talk/"&gt;62_GCBC Talk Herbert Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../a-day-in-a-sloans-life/"&gt;A Day In A Sloan’s
Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 13:12:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-03-16:confession-stanford-sloan-fellow-summary</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#59 - Course Evaluation_Spring Q</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/course-evaluation-spring-Q</link><description>&lt;p&gt;....continued from &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/?p=2433"&gt;Course Evaluation_Winter
Q&lt;/a&gt; ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the last one in this CIDRAE Evaluation Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/CIDRAE_Spring.png" width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 12:34:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-07-03:course-evaluation-spring-Q</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#58 - Course Evaluation_Winter Q</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/course-evaluation-winter-q</link><description>&lt;p&gt;... continued from &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_37_fall-qtr-course-final-evaluation/"&gt;Course Evaluation_Fall
Q&lt;/a&gt;
...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit overdue, from Winter Q, which seems like a distant past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/CIDRAE_Winter.png", width="800px", alt="Winter Qtr Course Evaluation"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 12:34:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-07-01:course-evaluation-winter-q</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#53 - 10 Things To Do Before Coming to Stanford Sloan Master Program</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/10-things-to-do-before-coming-to-stanford-sloan-master-program</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In descending order of importance,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complete your &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/herbertyang"&gt;Linkedin
    profile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linkedin has been used extensively by business schools, head
    hunters, and HR recruitment officers of many companies in US.
    It's gone mainstream and become a must-have in Stanford GSB. If
    you're looking for a job after Stanford, you can probably afford
    not to have a Facebook account, but you can't afford to have no
    Linkedin account. Linkedin helps to validate your professional
    history and it currently owns this market space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your personal linkedin URL and don't use the default
    system-generated random link, which no one remembers and
    looks amateurish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend quality time to polish and complete the Linkedin profile.
    A well updated Linkedin profile takes long time to fine-tune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategize on your personal branding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think long and hard about how you want others to label/perceive
    you in KISS (Keep It Simple and Stupid) terms, for example, that startup guy, the VC dude,
    the hard-core quant guy, the non-profit lady, the corporate
    dude, the inventor genius, that marketing girl, etc. Ideally you
    want this reputation to precede yourself because that's how
    people start paying attention to you and pointing resources to
    you, in a crowded market filled with over-achievers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 months fly by fast. The race of getting attention starts
    right on the first day when you land on campus. The earlier you
    can establish your personal brand/reputation, the more milage
    you can get out of your limited days in Stanford's universe. In
    fact, once you start promoting yourself with a solid brand that
    conveys what you bring and what you're looking for, many new
    friends and resources will start aligning around you naturally
    without you even trying. Yeah, it's magical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you've identified the personal brand for yourself, don't
    change it. It's pretty costly to change a product positioning.
    The same goes for a personal brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know what you want to get out of Stanford/Sloan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We come to Stanford Sloan for &lt;a href="../../../2012/08/live-stanford-life-to-the-fullest/"&gt;many different
    reasons&lt;/a&gt;.
    Some are looking for career transition; some are looking for
    knowledge; some are looking for business partners; some are
    looking for validation; some are looking for professor's
    attention; some are looking for friends; some are looking for
    dates; some are looking for babies, some are just looking for
    chill. Our goal determines our plan; our plan determines how we
    will use our most precious asset - time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I'm looking for inspirations and partners. Coming from a
    pretty extensive business and finance background, I try to
    unlearn frameworks and theories that I deem no longer relevant
    or useful to me. I try to keep as little things in my mind as
    possible so that my mind can stay in its most vigilant and
    free-roaming state. Besides that, I spend a lot of time hanging
    out with  my classmates in various activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare for the accounting exemption exam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to opt out of Accounting (a core course) in Summer
    Quarter, you need to take the Accounting exemption exam a few
    days before the start of Summer Quarter.  For my year it was an
    open-book, closed-door, fixed-time exam. Many students with
    finance background took it, got exempted, and enrolled into
    critically-acclaimed Professor Charles Lee's Alphanomics - a
    highly sought-after class for those quant-minded hard-core
    finance students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who get exempted from Accounting, they have to take
    another finance-themed class of more advanced level. I've gone
    soft over the years and not hard-core at all now, and I didn't
    intend to build myself into an investment guru in Stanford GSB.
    So I didn't take the Accounting exemption exam. It was much
    easier to get by in basic Accounting than Alphanomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy the latest Macbook Air&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple's Macbook Air (not Macbook Pro) is hands down the best
    overall notebook for business school students. It's light, fast,
    powerful, and sleek. If your're about to change for a new
    notebook, use your Stanford email/ID to enjoy the student
    discount and get the latest model of Macbook Air. There might be
    lighter notebooks out there like Sony/Samsung, but they're using
    Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This is getting off the track a bit) All your personal files,
    including digital media ones (mainly photos), should be stored
    in some combination of Dropbox, Skydrive, Box, and Google Drive, the four most prominent cloud storage services. No additional
    back-up is needed. (However, as of April 2014, I'm moving away from all the above cloud services and switching to BitTorrent Sync)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on what car you want to buy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you decide you'll eventually need a car in the Bay Area, make
    the purchase decision as early as possible. The further away
    you're deferring this decision, the more money you'll be losing
    on the car you buy. Buying a car early in the Summer brings you
    a world of benefits and goodwill. Do not procrastinate. Make
    this the No.2 priority after arriving in SFO. (No.1 priority is
    to get a local phone number with 650 zip code)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Car-purchase decision in US can be done entirely on the
    Internet, where you can find anything you need for this very
    mature market. You can ping down which car dealer has the exact
    car you want and close the transaction in one day. For me I got
    my local phone number on Day 2 and bought the car on Day 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a related note, get a California driver's license and a State
    ID as early as you can. Do not count on using your
    home-country's driver's license for the entire Sloan year, which
    is doable but not advisable, at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare for BBLs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="../../../2012/12/my-bbl/"&gt;BBL&lt;/a&gt;
    is one of the most amazing experiences out of Sloan Program and
    it should not be taken lightly. They form a very strong and
    intimate bonding among Sloans. Based on our
    preferences/requests, staff will schedule the BBL sessions for
    all the Sloans throughout the entire academic year (usually 4
    BBLs during one lunch session).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the golden rule: &lt;em&gt;the earlier you can finish your BBL,
    the better&lt;/em&gt;. Just like in any other typical new social
    environment, people's interest in getting to know others is at
    peak level when the party just starts,  then it gradually slows
    down and diminishes as the party is coming to the end, since
    most people already form their own social circles and know who
    they want to hang out with. You do not want to be sitting at the
    end of that
    &lt;a href="../../../2013/03/sloan-fellow-life-cycle-how-to-make-the-most-out-of-it/"&gt;curve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring your national costumes, for BBLs, and also for culture
    night parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identify your dinner targets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the same &lt;a href="../../../2013/03/sloan-fellow-life-cycle-how-to-make-the-most-out-of-it/"&gt;life-cycle analysis for the 12-month
    period&lt;/a&gt;, Summer and Fall Quarters are the best time to make some new
    friends before MBAs take over the airwave and we're swamped by
    rigorous academic workload in Winter Quarter. No matter how busy
    you think you are in Summer Quarter, it'll be nothing compared
    to Winter Quarter. Check out the profiles of your fellow
    students before
    arriving on campus and start scheduling 1-1/2-2 lunch/dinner
    with them. In Winter Quarter private dinner time with another
    Sloan will be a luxury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know what class officer role you want to play&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the 12-month period, probably more than half of my class will have performed some class officer roles. While every
    class officer role entails something very different, it's
    advisable to step up and do something for your class, especially
    when you have a generally forgiving crowd to work with. As my
    &lt;a href="../../../2012/08/chair-analysis/"&gt;previous
    analysis demonstrates&lt;/a&gt;, social chair has the highest reward/effort ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design your own namecards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a highly idiosyncratic move but I think it's worth
    trying. We don't have to use the standard business card from the
    program that has the Stanford logo. We can just design our &lt;a href="../../../2012/12/a-new-business-card/"&gt;own
    name cards with a
    style&lt;/a&gt;. It will
    stand out easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then how do we print the Stanford logo on our own namecards? I
    would not even bother. If the recipient of my namecard doesn't
    even believe I'm from Stanford as I claim, then he/she probably
    does not deserve to receive my namecard in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In true Hollywood spirit, this is the prequel to my previous post
&lt;a href="../../../2012/06/survival-guide-for-the-first-three-days/"&gt;Survival Guide for the First Three
Days&lt;/a&gt;,
the first article in this running series of &lt;a href="../../../../tag/coassf"&gt;Confession of a Stanford
Sloan Fellow (aka,
COASSF)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 22:12:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-18:10-things-to-do-before-coming-to-stanford-sloan-master-program</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#52 - Stanford Business Magazine Quote</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/stanford-business-magazine-quote</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It was a very pleasant surprise when I read the back page of 2013 Spring
Issue of &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/news/bmag"&gt;Stanford Business
Magazine&lt;/a&gt;. Surprise #1, this was
actually a very accurate quote from me, though I have no idea how the
magazine got it. Surprise #2, the editor thoughtfully used my previous
Facebook profile photo instead of the current Jack Sparrow one ... nice
touch there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the mysterious friend out there who tipped this off to the magazine
staff, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Stanford-Magazine-01.jpg", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Stanford-Magazine-02.jpg", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 14:03:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-17:stanford-business-magazine-quote</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#48 - My Yearbook Message</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/my-yearbook-message-for-Stanford-Sloan</link><description>&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of sitting right next to my Sloan-mate Nicki Carter, who is co-leading an admirable and spirited effort of publishing Yearbook of Sloan Class of 2013,  is that I can rest assured to receive regular reminder about my yearbook message status for no less than ... four times a week. After leading Nicki's "Hall of Shame" for many weeks in a row, I decided to redeem  myself in front of Nicki and get it over with. For someone with a petty education background prior to Stanford, I actually don't think I've ever written a yearbook message before. So I did a bit of research to see what this whole yearbook message thing is about in US, and I've arrived at the following takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;writing the yearbook message could be quite an effort, especially if&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you want to stand out and leave something others can remember you by&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the message should be original, creative, witty, and memorable, to say the least; being inspirational or cruel will be a plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use quotes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending a few hours to dig out some old emails and blogs, I came up with my yearbook message, finally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"At first, I was afraid, I was petrified. Kept thinking, I could never do this well with all of you shining by my side. But then I spent so many minutes thinking, how I came here. And I grew strong and I learned how to introduce myself." - &lt;em&gt;first meeting&lt;/em&gt;, July 1, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Social is the path to the bright side. Social leads to fun. Fun leads to happiness. Happiness leads to friends" - &lt;em&gt;Social Chair Report on Class Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, July 25, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I engage, I entertain, I enthrall” – &lt;em&gt;CMC Linkedin workshop&lt;/em&gt;, Aug 10, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Study Hard, Social Harder" - &lt;em&gt;Class Meeting&lt;/em&gt;, Aug 22, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I'm S-ettling down in CA + S-tarting a new business + S-eeking friends &amp;amp; partners" - &lt;em&gt;BBL&lt;/em&gt;, Oct 1, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"At times of uncertainties or Act of God, do not panic, do not question, do not hesitate, just follow my command" - &lt;em&gt;Gangnam Style flash mob&lt;/em&gt;, Oct 12, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This would triumph all other accomplishments we could possibly amass in the Sloan program" - &lt;em&gt;Stanford NCAA Men's Basketball Game half-time show&lt;/em&gt;, Nov 12, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Our distinguished project team consists of trendy investment bankers, experienced corporate executives, swashbuckling management consultants, illuminary government dignitaries, and Simon" - &lt;em&gt;Generative Leadership group presentation by Lost Child&lt;/em&gt;, Nov 30, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"And so Sally can't wait, she knows we're too brave as we're dancing on by. Her mind blown away, and don't look back in sadness. We're here to stay. " - &lt;em&gt;The Spillovers Debut&lt;/em&gt;, Dec 12, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Whatever happens in Seatle, stays in Seatle" - &lt;em&gt;Seatle study trip&lt;/em&gt;, Dec 15, 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Estonia and Sweden, Join hands, join hands together, We're friends forever' - &lt;em&gt;Lake Tahoe Ski Trip #1&lt;/em&gt;, Jan 19, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Story leads to discovery; discovery leads to enlightenment; enlightenment leads to happiness" - &lt;em&gt;Chinese New Year Party&lt;/em&gt;, Feb 08, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Is this the real life? Is this just fantasy? Caught in a landslide. No escape from reality. Open your eyes. Look up to the skies and see." - &lt;em&gt;Lake Tahoe Ski Trip #2&lt;/em&gt;, Feb 16, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Though you might be hiding away from the madding crowd in Hotel California listening to the Wind of Change, The Spillovers will Twist and Shout, and play With or Without You. After all, It's My Life and I Hate Myself For Loving You. As long as you Smell Like a Teen Spirit, I Wish You Were Here and I Don't Want To Miss A Thing by letting go the last chance of amusing you before you go on the epic East Coast Trip. Don't Cry... this is not Touchy Feely. This is from The Spillovers. Out.”  &lt;em&gt;The Spillovers Curtain Call&lt;/em&gt;, Mar 21, 2013&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 17:29:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-10:my-yearbook-message-for-Stanford-Sloan</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#47 - Sloan Fellow Life Cycle &amp; How To Make The Most Out Of It</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/sloan-fellow-life-cycle-how-to-make-the-most-out-of-it</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Before we know, 8 months have flown by and now we're 4 months away from
graduation. All good things will come to an end, and our wonderful
journey at Sloan Fellow Program in Stanford GSB is of no exception. The
question is: how can we make the most out of this 12-month period?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the Fall Quarter from October to December is the "sweet spot"
that we should take the most advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Sloan-Life-Cycle.png", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to forming relationship and bonding with our fellow
Sloans, there are two dominant factors that will influence how much we
can put in and how much we can get out. One is &lt;em&gt;time available for
socializing&lt;/em&gt; with the classmates, and the other one is our &lt;em&gt;desire to bond&lt;/em&gt;
with others in the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By my observation and analysis, our desire to bond with other Sloans
roughly follows a curve (red one in the diagram) where: 1) overall it's
always increasing (of course); 2) it's accelerating in the first half
and decelerating in the second half. That convection point occurs
somewhere in Fall Quarter or Winter Quarter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Summer Quarter&lt;/em&gt;, we take all the classes together and we're the only
one on campus (MBAs are out doing internships). So the classic grouping
dynamic plays out - we're curious to find out everyone's background and
try to stack ourselves against the group to find out where we stand.
This is the period where personal reputation is built from the classroom
discussions and group projects. On average a Sloan may not be able to
call out everyone else's name yet in the class, but we're getting there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Fall Quarter&lt;/em&gt;, the accumulative social activities have gradually been
adding up to a critical mass to enable most Sloans to remember everyone
else's name in the class. The most aggressive alpha males (or females)
have already identified themselves and stepped up to take some class
officer roles to serve the class and make their presence felt. Sloans
still take most of the classes together. A variety of personality types
are flashing out and bumping with each other. We still take study groups
pretty seriously and try to get decent scores. The MBAs have arrived in
Knight Management Center but they are preoccupied with orientation and
neither camp has the bandwidth to reach out to the other side yet.
Dinners with Sloans are still possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Winter Quarter&lt;/em&gt;, things are getting really hectic as
academic curriculum is taking a hefty toll and the daunting prospect of
finding that dream job is looming on the horizon. Sloans on average are
in 3 - 4 study groups working on different projects. Most people seem to
be taking around 20 units. Two streams of classes are killing people
left and right: 1) hard-core investment/finance classes; 2) startup
classes. We are only taking Marketing and Finance together and it feels
like we never get to see certain classmates in this quarter. This is
also when we start taking many classes with MBAs. Stanford MBAs are
pretty solid and sometimes more fun. Some Sloans start hanging out with
MBAs and spending even less time with each other. At the same time, many
Sloans begin their job search and cut down the time in holding hands
with other Sloans singing jambalaya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where we stand now. Looking forward at &lt;em&gt;Spring Quarter&lt;/em&gt;, I can see
Sloans will be struggling to strike a balance between two competing
forces: 1) the singular goal of finding a job and stay in the Bay area;
2) the desire to solidify friendship and spend more time with Sloans as
every day that goes by reminds us that the clock is ticking and we're
walking out of a beautiful fantasy dreamland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the desire for bonding, time available for social activities is
another important factor that will shape the group dynamics. Summer
Quarter looks like a walk in the park now - we even had regular weekly
basketball games! It's hard to believe we had so much free time then! It
certainly didn't feel that way when we were in it - maybe because we
were still taking the courses pretty seriously and reading every case
assigned. Fall Quarter's Accounting class alone will usher many people
into recurring nightmares and reduce their social drive, but it is still
not too bad as we still have a sizable group that goes to Wednesday's
ETL regularly. In Winter Quarter people start disappearing all together,
or simply just go different ways into various BBLs, seminars,
conferences, across-the-street classes, endless market-research
interviews for startup projects, etc. People are worrying less about the
qualify of academic work and just want to finish the work and move on.
People are exploring Stanford/Bay area at large and paying much less
attention to Knight Management Center. Very few people can afford to
attend the ETL series. Dinner time with Sloans becomes a luxury. In
Spring Quarter, the key focus for the self-sponsored Sloans will be job
search and job search. We might see a slight rebound in time put aside
for social activities, but I doubt it's going to be anything
substantial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given all the forces in the universe that are pushing us into
various directions, it seems that Fall Quarter is the "&lt;em&gt;sweet spot&lt;/em&gt;" where
Sloans still have considerable desire to social and are able to afford
the time. Carpe diem!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 20:36:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-03-04:sloan-fellow-life-cycle-how-to-make-the-most-out-of-it</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#46 - Comparison of S353 (Formation of New Venture) and G566 (Real-Life Ethics)</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/comparison-S353-and-G566-in-GSB</link><description>&lt;p&gt;G566 Real-Life Ethics was my &lt;a href="../../../2013/01/fall-qtr-course-evaluation/"&gt;most favorite class in the Fall
Quarter&lt;/a&gt;
and S353 is my most favorite class in the current Winter Quarter. They
share a lot of similarities, but resonate with me at very different
levels. Here's a detailed breakdown of comparison between them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/G566vsS353_All.png", alt="Compare S353 and G566", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 15:20:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-02-28:comparison-S353-and-G566-in-GSB</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#45 - Should You Do Stanford's Famous Startup Courses?</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/should-you-do-stanfords-famous-startup-courses</link><description>&lt;p&gt;As my prior article "&lt;a href="../15-things-to-know-in-strategizing-your-course-portfolio/"&gt;15 Things to Know in Strategizing Your Stanford
Courses&lt;/a&gt;"
mentioned, doing one of those startup-themed courses (E245, S321) feels
almost like a rite of passage for many Stanford MBA/Sloans. So, should
you just go and do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends. Here's the decision tree I'd recommend. If you need more
insight, contact me in private. I don't pass isolated judgement on any
GSB course in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14612386414" title="Startup-Course-Enrollment by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2900/14612386414_5e235a9144_b.jpg" width="640"  alt="Startup-Course-Enrollment"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 16:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-02-19:should-you-do-stanfords-famous-startup-courses</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#43 - Where Is Stanford Sloan Fellow?</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/where-is-stanford-sloan-fellow</link><description>&lt;p&gt;At this historical moment, as we are turning the page for a new chapter
for the Stanford Sloan Fellow program, it's important to remind
ourselves where we stand in the universe. For people in similar career
stage as me, this is the best program in the world, bar none.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/Where-is-Sloan.png", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 09:31:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-31:where-is-stanford-sloan-fellow</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#42 - 15 Things to Know in Strategizing Your Sloan Courses</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/15-things-to-know-in-strategizing-your-course-portfolio</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the first week of the third quarter of my 12-month Sloan academic
year, I find myself spending at least 2-3 hours every day this week in a
perpetual (often futile ) attempt to optimize my courses for this
quarter. The exhaustive and reiterative process has been very tiring,
but much needed. Because the course selection of Winter Quarter is
critical, unique and sets the course for half of my Sloan year. In
Summer and Fall Quarter, our curriculum was largely the same with
limited variations - there was not much we can do to adjust the
curriculum. Things start getting interesting in Winter Quarter, when we
only have two classes together (Finance and Marketing) and need to fill
up more than 50% of our academic calendar with self-selected coures from
GSB and other school. The below 15 factors, in descending order of
importance, might be helpful in strategizing your most optimal course
portfolio, from the perspective of a GSB Sloan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iconic Courses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the signature courses that have achieved immortal status in
Stanford lore. Most Stanford alumni have taken them or at least
auditioned them just so that they can proudly claim they have been to
Stanford. Even non-Stanford people from around the world follow those
courses religiously online from many open-course platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://etl.stanford.edu/"&gt;MS&amp;amp;E 472: Entrepreneurial Thought Leader's Seminar
("ETL")&lt;/a&gt;  You should make it a ritual to
attend this star-stubbed seminar at 430pm on every Wednesday. This is
the one seminar that rules them all, that bonds all Stanford students
from all the disciplines together. You can also easily get one credit if
you care to. Enrollment is easy as long as you have no scheduling
conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/class/cs106a/"&gt;CS 106A: Programming
Methodology&lt;/a&gt;. Legend has it that
90% of Stanford students have taken this introductory programming
course, which does not require any prior programming experience. We're
in Silicon Valley and Stanford. It just feels wrong not to take this
course to at least understand how coders work and think. Anyone with any
significance in Silicon Valley is most likely linked to Stanford in some
way, and most people have taken CS106A. So you're truly in the company
of some future movers and shakers of our time. While enrolling into this
course for credit with the undergraduates 3 times a week is probably a
bit of a stretch, you can always audition it or watch the online video.
Enrollment is easy as it's a huge lecture class with a roaster of a few
hundred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=STRAMGT+354%3A+Entrepreneurship+and+Venture+Capital&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;STRAMGT 354: Entrepreneurship and Venture
Capital&lt;/a&gt;.
The most sought-after Stanford GSB course, and the most difficult one to
get into. People weep in tears upon the news of enrollment. Valley
extraordinaires Peter Wendell, Andy Rachleff, and Eric Schmidt co-teach
this class. They have enormous pull from Sand Hill Road and Silicon
Valley, and thus regularly invite first-class entrepreneurs and VCs to
the classroom to share their insights. Wendell brought in &lt;a href="http://www.khoslaventures.com/people_vk.html"&gt;Vinod
Khosla&lt;/a&gt; in the first class
of the quarter last week, as if just to make a statement. You have to
super-round this one to have the chance to get in as every GSBer is
throwing his/her super-round option on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=FINANCE+321%3A+Investment+Management+and+Entrepreneurial+Finance&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;Finance 321: Investment Management
and Entrepreneurial Finance&lt;/a&gt;.
The legendary 7-unit course taught by celebrated value investor Jack
McDonald (to give an idea, most courses are 2-3 units; 4 units is
considered pretty heavy; 5 units is very rare; 7 units is out of this
world). If you're going to do investment of any kind, you should try to
enroll into this class. Auditioning attempt will be futile. McDonald has
a photographic memory even at his current age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?page=1&amp;amp;q=interpersonal+dynamics&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;view=catalog&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;OB374: Interpersonal
Dynamics&lt;/a&gt;.
The famous "touchy feely" course in GSB that everyone is talking about.
All my Sloan classmates who are taking this course are raving about it
and many GSBers think this is the single best course in all their GSB
years. As someone who has watched David Finch's Fight Club (1999) many
times, the mere thought of "touch feely” brings up vivid pictures of a
support group therapy session, where everyone is crying over the
shoulders of someone else, and occasionally Edward Norton buries his
head in Meat Loaf's man-boobs...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity Professors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many illuminaries, Sillicon legends, Nobel laureates, and billionnaires
walked the corridors of Knight Management Center. There are so many of
them in this pantheon of gods that it'll be almost an insult to them to
single-out any individual ones. There are some larger-than-life
personalities whose mere presence will enthrall people in awe such
as: &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/jmcdonal"&gt;Jack McDonald&lt;/a&gt; (GSB's
franchise professor), &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/agrove"&gt;Andrew
Grove&lt;/a&gt; (Intel),
and &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/condi"&gt;Condoleezza
Rice&lt;/a&gt; (Secretary of State);
there are some glittering entrepreneurs/VCs whose names have been heard
by every GSBer such as &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/pwendell"&gt;Peter
Wendell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://engineering.stanford.edu/profile/sblank"&gt;Steve
Blank&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/rachleff"&gt;Andy
Rachleff&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/mleslie1"&gt;Mark
Leslie&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://ecorner.stanford.edu/author/heidi_roizen"&gt;Heidi
Roizen&lt;/a&gt;; there are many
Nobel winners in GSB, such as &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/mscholes"&gt;Myron
Scholes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/users/mspence"&gt;A. Michael
Spence&lt;/a&gt;; there are also
some filthily rich professor billionaire such as  &lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/~cheriton/"&gt;David
Cheriton&lt;/a&gt; (who famously wrote
Google's first check). There are many, many more. You're in Stanford.
Nobody gets to teach here by being less than a superstar in his/her own
right. Even for the professors who classes we don't quite enjoy, I can
see why they can stand here on a solid ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Juicy Startup Courses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://startup.gsb.stanford.edu/"&gt;S356: Startup Garage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/class/msande273/"&gt;M273: Technology Venture
Formation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://e245.stanford.edu/"&gt;E245: The Lean Launchpad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=STRAMGT+321%3A+Create+a+New+Venture%3A+From+Idea+to+Launch+I&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;S321: Create a New Venture, From Idea to
Launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many think it's a rite of passage to do a startup-themed course in
Stanford - which is probably true, especially for those who haven't done
startup before. The above four are your choices, among which two are
from School of Engineering. Choose them carefully because it's a
significant undertaking. You should expect to spend 15-30 hours a week,
which include class time, many hours of team meetings, and regular
review sessions with assigned mentors. All of them require application
as a team. S356 and S321 are heavy two-quarter commitments (you can
still get out after one quarter but it might create bad will with your
team), while M273 and E245 are one-quarter only. I will try to do a more
in-depth analysis and comparison among these courses in a separate
article. Make sure you choose the right team  (3-4) for these coures
because you'll spend significant hours together, much more than a
typical study group format requires. Grouping with the wrong person for
3 months is much worse than sitting in the wrong class. You sort of
place a big bet of your social capital (ie. time) on 3 people
(Sloan/MBA/engineer) at the expense of the other 70-80 Sloans. Good
luck. Another great benefit of these courses is the mentor the
instructor will assign to you, and the opportunity to pitch to real VCs
for your project. For people who are new to this process, this will be a
great experience to get hands dirty and get a taste of how it's like
working in startups and with VCs. For people who have gone through this
process before, don't get too dizzy with all the shining names from Sand
Hill. It takes several reciprocal transactions to start building a real
business relationship. MBAs have more means at their disposal such as
independent studies, case-writing, teaching assistant etc. As Sloans,
we're in general a bit handicapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reasonable Course Portfolio Strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's helpful to have a rough roadmap before coming to Stanford Sloan in
terms of what you want to get out of it, then allocate your courses (or,
your tuition) strategically. I suggest strategizing your portfolio of
courses around the below major categories: A) Startup track; B)
Corporate Track; C) Investment Track; D) Social Innovation ; E)
International Politics &amp;amp; Economies;  F) Leadership. G) Communication
(this is for Sloans only. Few Sloans would go Consulting after
graduation). It's advisable to major in only one stream from A to E,
maybe minor in another stream from F to G, then taste the rest with a
surveyor mentality. &lt;em&gt;Do not major in two streams&lt;/em&gt;. It will kill your
social calendar and cost you the most valuable asset you can get out of
Sloan program - bonding with other Sloans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A&lt;/em&gt; is self-explanatory - you do whatever you want to do in the
wilderness, do 1-2 above mentioned startup course; sign up for every
course that has "entrepreneurship" in its title from every school;
attend weekly ETL religiously; hack your way into Wendell's class; watch
every video from &lt;a href="http://ecorner.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford's e-Corner&lt;/a&gt;;
attend as many Silicon Valley TMT conferences as your budget allows;
enroll into CS106A just to show you're hard-core; and make some young
friends in School of Computer Science or Engineering who only enjoy
coding for the pure pleasure of coding regardless of how lousy the
actual product/service is - which inevitably is designed by you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;B&lt;/em&gt; is for people with corporate sponsorship or willing to go back to the
corporate environment. Sign up for some bad-ass named courses such as
&lt;a href="http://csi.gsb.stanford.edu/the-paths-to-power"&gt;Paths to Power&lt;/a&gt;,
Decision for the Future, etc. Minoring in either leadership or
communication goes well with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;C&lt;/em&gt; has three sub-streams: angel/VC investment, private equity investment,
and public investment (hedge fund and portfolio management). They all
lead to very different industry dynamics, practices, and locations so
you want to think carefully before stepping into any stream. Get into
the class of Jack McDonald, Peter Wendell, and Charles Lee. Run for
Sloan Class' Investment Committee officer position. Show up at every
event whenever any member of Stanford Management Company (Stanford's
endowment fund) is present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D is D. E is a common choice for Sloans sponsored by governments or
coming from family business background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flashy One-Timers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's important to take note of some highly desired courses that are only
offered in a particular quarter (due to the availability of the
instructor, who might be attending multiple board meetings or making
movies, or advising US President in the other three quarters). For
example, Jack McDonald's legendary 7-unit course on investment and
entrepreneur finance (Fall Quarter), Leadership in Entertainment
Business (Spring Quarter), and Real-Life Ethics (Fall Quarter). Take
them before they vanish from your academic year's calendar, which is
only one-year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heavy Two-Quarter Commitments&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many courses run across two continuous quarters because they use team
projects as the teaching vehicle. Make sure you sign up for the first
leg at the right quarter, otherwise it'll be very difficult to join them
at the second leg. That being said, there are still ways to join the
second leg of some of those courses. For example, when some people drop
from a team after the first leg, a position may become available and the
instructor may want to fill that with someone new just to keep the
group/project/class going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Confusing Application-Required Courses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MyGSB and Axess are the main portals to register for our courses, but
not always. Some courses require application and may not even been
available to register from Axess. There are three types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration available on Axess + No application needed. This is easy. Just register on Axess and you're set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration available on Axess + Application needed. Very confusing. You have registered the course on Axess, but you still
have to go through a separate application process outside of Axess to
get enrolled, which means your precious calendar will be taken up by a
course that is not guaranteed to you yet and at the same time might get
in your way for other courses. The Spirit of Entrepreneurship and Lean
Launchpad come to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration not available on Axess + Application needed Less confusing but more mysterious. They are not on Axess, you have to
go to their own idiosyncratic websites to apply or even go through the
draconian means of ... email. Sloan's staff does a pretty good job on
this and will organize talks before the registration period to highlight
all such courses that need special attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evil Exams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps to go for the electives that have no exams - so that you will
be free in the last exam-week and start your vacation earlier while
others are still sweating on exams. It seems that most electives do not
have exams, but some of them do have, such as Decision for the Future.
Be aware and stay away from those courses, unless you really love them
dearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shining Guest Speakers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you evaluate the attractiveness of a course, the quantity and the
quality of its guest speakers are very important. They can make a huge
difference and bring life to an otherwise dreadful classroom session.
They also reflect how influential the professor is and how much pull
he/she's got in the industry and around the Silicon Valley. For many
classes guest speakers are integral part of the teaching, such as Real
Estate Investment, Real-Life Ethics, Entrepreneurship: Formation of New
Ventures, The Spirit of Entrepreneurship, Election 2012, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bright MBAs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the core courses are Sloan-only. Some electives are set up to be
Sloan-only (such as Executive Communications). Most electives have mix
of MBAs and Sloans. Personally it's been an enlightening experience for
me to take many clases with MBAs, who are smart, respectful and mature
(despite of their much younger average age).  I wish I could have spent
more time with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geeky Coders and Engineers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attend some classes "across the street" from School of Engineering or
School of Computer Science. Stanford GSB students can rival the best
MBAs from any school, including Harvard and Wharton, but still they are
not the prince of the universe here. Don't lose the sight of the fact
that Silicon Valley's culture, wealth, and social pecking order are
defined and ruled by engineers and coders from Stanford. It will pay
long-term dividend to make some friends there and at least understand
how they work and think. Besides attending ETL and CS106A, go to some
seminars/talks organized by Engineering and Computer Science. Don't get
too caught up in Knight Management Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personalized Seasonality&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many Sloans regularly taking around 20 credits a quarter, it's
fairly easy to satisfy the academic requirements for graduation, which
ask for 56 credits, out of which at least 50 come from GSB. Summer
Quarter is pretty light with only 12 credits (we played many basketball
games then - utterly unthinkable now);  Fall Quarter and Winter Quarter
are the heaviest. You do have some level of discretion about Spring
Quarter. You can either load yourself up to attend as many classes as
you can to make good on your \$108,000 tuition investment, or go by with
only 11 credits - the lowest credits you have to maintain to qualify as
a full-time student.  You can free up yourself to pursue other things in
life, such as landing a job, finding a significant other, starting a
business, or making some babies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manageable Team Relationships&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every class requires some sort of grouping. So we always end up
in 4-6 different groups in Fall/Winter/Spring Quarter. Most of them are
only called for on as-needed basis when group project deliverables are
approaching. However, be aware that some groups are quite heavy-lifting
and require significant investment in time and emotion (like "Touchy
Feely") due to the nature of the group projects. All the startup-themed
classes, as well as the assigned study group for Finance and Marketing,
fall into this category. Depending what kind of people you end up with
in your groups, some groups choose to meet as little as possible and
some groups prefer to do everything together. Welcome to B-school, where
drama never ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forgotten Audition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not forget to audit. Many a time you're not able to enroll into a
particular class for reasons such as, you max out your 22 credits for
the quarter, the class is full, it conflicts with other classes on your
calendar, etc. You can still sit in for those classes as long as the
instructor permits. You sit in the back row; do not raise your hand; no
participation, no homework, no grade; you're just a spectator - this is
auditing. I would always audit for Wendell's class as long as I'm not
completely burned out. With so many intellectually stimulating classes
opening their doors to you left and right, it'll be a crime and waste of
your tuition money if you don't do any auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Precious Wednesday&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last and the least, try to keep your Wednesday free of any class except
ETL, which is always on Wednesday afternoon. Sloan staff usually
schedules program-related activities on Wednesday, such as important
announcements or class meetings. Many study groups schedule their weekly
session on Wednesday.  You should also leave some room for yourself for
interviews, out-of-town trips. An inconveniently timed class on
Wednesday might screw up all such schedules and make you very unpopular
in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voila!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 21:22:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-26:15-things-to-know-in-strategizing-your-course-portfolio</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#39 - Reflection Notes from S353 Jan 15</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/reflection-notes-from-s353-jan-15</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reflected from today's S353 Entrepreneurship: Formation of New Business,
Case SHED:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 is the best number for the size of a startup team (even Google's
    Brin and Page had to bring Schmidt to balance out). 4 is usually not
    very stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not split equity equally. It rarely works out. In the case of 3
    founders, make sure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a single largest shareholder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The equity stake of any two founders is greater than the third
    one's&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not discuss equity split until there is a tangible idea to work
    on and everyone knows what his/her role is. Discussion on equity
    split, once occurred, is very difficult to roll back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not form a partnership only based on common interests, or purely
    based on friendship. Every condition below has to be met before
    forming a startup partnership:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;same value system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;common interest areas (entertainment, mobile Internet,
    healthcare, agriculture... something)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a business idea that all parties agree to commit to (could be a
    vague one.. but there has to be one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;complementary skill set&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vetting on team members during GSB days is essential, but may not be
    sufficient. A man's true character and personality are only revealed
    when there is significant money at stake. TGIFs, study group
    discussions, coffee breaks at Coupa, study trips, all these
    interactions certainly help to understand someone's value system and
    integrity, but founders should not get too carried away on those
    findings. When there is no real money at play, it's not hard to get
    along with most people in GSB. GSB's environment, compared to
    real-life startup situations, is not stressful enough to put a man
    in a corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of defensible and sustainable business model is
    over-rated (Monitor Group did go bankrupt). A startup play is to
    arbitrage on the constraint optimization. When other players in the
    market see the same potential, that arbitrage opportunity will
    diminish unless the company reinvents itself. Everything is in
    relative sense - a startup is only as successful as the founders are
    able to exit with respectable return before it's lost its edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attending trade shows to get business ideas? This might work in the
    case of SHED, but I won't use that as the main source of idea
    generation. My problem, and my partners' problem, has always been
    that we have way too many ideas we want to work on, and we only have
    limited resources. I've never been in a situation like, oh my god, I
    have no idea what to start up with. Let me go attend a trade show to
    get some ideas. I get hit by ideas all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do founders know an idea is new? In our case, it's very simple.
    All three of us are very well informed and plugged in our own
    networks. If an idea pops up and none of us has heard about it
    before, almost by definition it has to be a new idea (otherwise we
    would have known).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of SHED case brings out a very interesting business
    strategy that is pretty rare but could be highly effective.
    Occasionally, a small player can leverage existing competition and
    play off against big players. For details, read Isaac Asimov's
    Foundation series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting a new business without domain expertise is very possible,
    as Sarah Blakely of Spanx, Tory Burch of Tory Burch, and Scott and
    Eric from SHED have demonstrated. With enough passion and
    dedication, it's not that hard to catch up on the knowledge and
    experience. It's not easy, but can be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-16:reflection-notes-from-s353-jan-15</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#38 - Sell Used Textbooks</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/sell-used-textbooks</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I paused for a while to mull over whether I should sell all my textbooks
from the summer and the fall quarter, or I should keep any individual
textbook. After pondering for 0.01 second, I decided to sell them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three ways to sell those used textbooks for cash: A) sell to
Stanford Bookstore for cash right away; B) trade in on Amazon.com for
Amazon gift card; C) Follow what I just did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sell to Stanford Bookstore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bkstr.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/BuybackMaterialsView?catalogId=10001&amp;amp;schoolStoreId=10161"&gt;search the ISBN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bring the books to Stanford Bookstore and get cash on the spot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trade in on Amazon.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;search the ISBN at this
&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Trade-In/b/ref=sv_b_0?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;node=2242532011"&gt;Amazon's Trade-in Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;follow the website's instructions, print out the
shipping label, and ship out the books by the required date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;receive an Amazon gift card&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arbitrage between Stanford Bookstore and Amazon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford Bookstore offers cash right away, but mostly at discounted
prices. For some books Amazon offers substantially higher prices (such
as Microeconomics and Financial Accounting), but you get an Amazon gift
card instead of cash, and Amazon may impose more strict conditions on
the books. You just have to strike a balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;here's my trades:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Amazon Trade-in List:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Strategic&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Management&lt;/span&gt;    
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9780470009475&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mo"&gt;047000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;9470&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;35.70&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Microeconomics&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;th&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Pearson&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Series&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Economics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;ISBN13:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9780131392632&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mo"&gt;01313&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;92638&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;97.51&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Business&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Its&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Environment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;th&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9780136083924&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mo"&gt;01360&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;83927&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;12.25&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;As&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;We&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Speak&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;How&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Make&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Your&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Point&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Have&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;It&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Stick&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9781439153086&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1439153086&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.00&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Modern&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Firm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Organizational&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Design&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Performance&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Growth&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9780198293750&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mo"&gt;01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;98293755&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.00&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Financial&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Accounting&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;rd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;third&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Edition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9781934319604&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ISBN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1934319600&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Expected&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Amount&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Per&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;96.05&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Total Value from Amazon Trade-in: $243.51&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Stanford Bookstore Cash For Books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Title:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Complete&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Business&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Statistics&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Edition:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Author:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;ACZEL&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Publisher:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;WOHL&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;PUBLISHING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;INC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;ISBN:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9781935938187&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Unit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;20.00&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Title:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Improv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Wisdom&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Edition:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Author:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;MADSON&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Publisher:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;CROWN&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;PUBLISHING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;GROUP&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;ISBN:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9781400081882&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Unit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;2.00&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Title:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Influence&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Edition:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;th&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Author:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;CIALDINI&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Publisher:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;PRENTICE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;HALL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;INC&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;ISBN:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9780205609994&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Unit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;4.00&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Title:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Redefining&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Global&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Strategy&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Edition:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Author:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;GHEMAWAT&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;Publisher:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;HARVARD&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;BUSINESS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SCHOOL&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nl"&gt;ISBN:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;9781591398660&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Unit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Price&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;4.00&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Total Value from Stanford Bookstore Trade-in: $30.00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 12:34:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-04:sell-used-textbooks</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#37 - Fall Quarter Course Final Evaluation</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/fall-qtr-course-evaluation</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My final evaluation for the Fall Quarter courses, following the CIDRAE
framework I developed in the summer. It's a somewhat scientific approach
to validate my favorite courses: Real-life Ethics, Election 2012,
Political Communication, Organization Behavior, and Generative
Leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final group presentation in Executive Communication was critiqued by
several judges of local Sloan alumni. We had a pleasant chat with one of
the judges after the team presentation, a young Sloan alumni with curly
hair, who gave us some thoughtful feedback. After getting through the
business stuff our conversation went casual and off the path. Seemingly
randomly he asked who had taken Real-Life Ethics. I identified myself
and went on a lengthy and passionate speech of flowery praise about how
much I enjoyed that class thoroughly and loved the instructor Mark
Leslie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of my speech, he smiled at me, I'm glad to hear that, Mark is
my father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.....o....k.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for an overview and introduction of CIDRAE, please read
&lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_24_evaluate-stanford-courses-with-cidrae/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:
| - to compare to the similar evaluation of my Summer Quarter courses,
please
read &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_25_summer-quarter-course-evaluation/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:
| - to compare to the interim evaluation of my Fall Quarter courses,
please read
&lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_26_fall-quarter-course-evaluation-interim/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="CIDRAE Score for Fall Qtr" src="../../../../images/CIDRAE_Fall-Qtr.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 23:45:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-03:fall-qtr-course-evaluation</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#34 - Application to dMedia</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/application-to-dmedia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dschool.stanford.edu/dmedia/"&gt;dMedia&lt;/a&gt; is a course from d.school
of Stanford in the coming Winter Quarter. As most other design-themed
courses from Stanford's trendy Design School, it has a
somewhat idiosyncratic application, in which I need to do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Share a single url that describes how your past experience has prepared
you to contribute to the dmedia class- a portfolio, a pdf, a flickr
page, a twitter feed, a video, an example of your work online-preferably
something we haven't thought of... it's up to you. Please make sure your
name &amp;amp; a title / description on the url is visible so we know it's you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I've laid out my answer in this page - why I think I can make a
meaningful contribution to the dmedia class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm familiar with developing mobile applications on
    smartphones.&lt;/em&gt; I've co-founded a startup that develops mobile
    applications (iOS &amp;amp; Android) leveraging the largest social network
    in China.Our app &lt;a href="http://www.zheli.com"&gt;zheli&lt;/a&gt;.com once made it into
    Top 10 in the Local Life Category in Apps Store
    China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/zheli.com.png", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have always been a visionary and evangelist&lt;/em&gt; when it comes to
    the smartphone revolution. I drew this chart in 2007, right after
    buying my first iPhone (Generation 1), and &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/apples-entire-consumer-strategy-and-vision-on-one-page/"&gt;made bold predictions
    about Apple's entire consumer
    strategy&lt;/a&gt;
    in the future. Most of my predictions have come into reality five
    years
    after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src ="../../../../images/apple-strategy.jpg", width="800px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm very experienced in creating enthralling entertainment
    contents&lt;/em&gt; for mass distribution. On Oct 12, 2012, I directed and
    produced the &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/confession-of-a-stanford-sloan-fellow_20_dance-of-my-life/"&gt;wildly successful Stanford GSB Flash
    Mob&lt;/a&gt;
    that took place in Stanford Knight Management Center on Oct 12, and
    made it into a viral hit on Youtube. On Nov 12, I led a team of 26
    Sloans to perform &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/gangnam-style-goes-to-stanford-ncaa-half-time-show/"&gt;Gangnam Style during the half-time show of
    Stanford Men's Basketball
    Game&lt;/a&gt;
    in Maples Pavilion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I'm a hard-core user on most of the prevailing SNS platforms&lt;/em&gt;,
    such as Facebook, Linkedin, Instagram, Weibo (China). I have &lt;a href="http://www.weibo.com/zire"&gt;12,892
    followers on Weibo&lt;/a&gt;, China's largest
    social network (similar to Twitter), and &lt;a href="http://instagram.com/zire"&gt;2,400 followers on
    Instagram&lt;/a&gt;. I know very well how SNS have
    evolved over the last few years. My guides/walkthroughs on using
    &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/how-i-learned-to-stop-worrying-and-love-the-weibo/"&gt;Weibo&lt;/a&gt;
    and
    &lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/instagram%EF%BC%8C%E6%91%84%E5%BD%B1%EF%BC%8C%E5%92%8C%E5%88%86%E4%BA%AB/"&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;
    have been widely quoted in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, I hope I have convinced you that I will be a valuable
addition to your class. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 02:48:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-12-20:application-to-dmedia</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#32 - GSB Reporter - Bubbles &amp; Flash Mob</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/from-gsb-reporter</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Business Reporter is Stanford Business School's quarterly
newspaper. It has no online presence and is distributed for free around
GSB's Knight Management Center. In this issue, our Sloan Class of 2013
contributed two articles, &lt;a href="http://sten.tamkivi.com/"&gt;Sten&lt;/a&gt;'s "The
Stanford Bubbles", and my "Recounting the Flash Mob". Our flash mob
videos can be found here, "&lt;a href="http://guizishanren.com/posts/2012/10/dance-of-my-life/"&gt;Dance of My
Life&lt;/a&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/13825179375" title="gsbreporter by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3714/13825179375_ca0b9a691d_c.jpg" width="777" height="800" alt="gsbreporter"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In sunny Friday afternoon on Oct 12, about eighty or so Sloans pulled
off a flash mob at GSB Town Square. Dancing to No.1 global hit Gangnam
Style. We surprised hundreds of unsuspicious students, faculties and
staff members with creative choreography, highly synchronized moves and
staggering number of participants. The public stunt brought excitement
to usually quiet Knight Management Center and was rewarded with
thunderous applause. The video synthesized clips from13 cameras and went
live on that Friday night. It went viral quickly on the Internet and
became a featured highlight on CNN's iReport on Oct 15. By Nov 7, the
video has attracted more than 200,000 views. At of now, Sloans are
scheduled to lead the half-time show for Stanford University Men’s
Basketball Game on Nov 12 in Maples Pavilion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few expected Sloans to do something so flamboyant, and few imagined our
ambitious flash mob project could become such a sensational success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a member of the core production team, I looked back at the past four
weeks feeling like walking out of a surreal dream, which surely has some
of my fondest GSB moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several lead dancers held their breath in dazzle and disbelief, when
Sangini, a professional local choreographer, taught us some basic moves
and stomped the floor ferociously in Sloan Lounge with a ballooning
belly for a baby that was due in four weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the dancers, "rub the towel" and "zip your pants" have now
taken whole new meanings. Certain actions speak louder than words. Oh
yeah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the flash mob, Sloans’ global supply chain's tour de
force was on full display when our campaign team orchestrated
coordinated effort between design firm in China and 24/7 printing outlet
in Palo Alto to rush out hundreds of poster prints for the marketing
blitz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mid-night of Oct 11, a cultish scene was sighted in GSB Town &amp;amp;
Square where close to a hundred figures were doing group dancing in
spooky silence. They came out of nowhere, left some mysterious markings
on the ground, and vanished into the darkness like ninjas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sloan partners, who are integral part of the program and immeasurably
more talented, also embraced the flash mob wholeheartedly by attending
in pacts every rehearsal session and even taking time off from work to
join the dance during lunch hour on Oct 12.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 11:45 AM on Oct 12, 2012, Sloans and partners marched fearlessly toward
Town &amp;amp; Square in drizzling rain with no hesitation or withdrawal but
only pride and courage. Our dance must have amused His Almighty that the
rain magically came to a stop. Town &amp;amp; Square saw the most beautiful sky
in all fall on that sunny afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the untimely rain, some of our dedicated camera crewmembers were
spotted holding ground-level cameras in unusually compromising
positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GSB Dean Garth Saloner, in company of Madhav Rajan and Mike
Hochleutner, calmly walked past our Mr. Psy and her gang of drrrty
dancers as if nothing had happened…Just another day in GSB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our video editor sat in front of an iMac for 12 hours straight,
copying and cutting clips from 13 cameras in awe-inspiring
professionalism, and almost missed her flight at 530am the next morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The No.1 burning question from Sloans during the following week: did
you find me in the video? Thanks to our families and friends all over
the world who each at least played the video five times trying to spot
us, the video's viewership just went through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot more, but we'll leave them in The Making of The Best
Flash Mob in Stanford History, Director's Cut, due next year on Sloan's
graduation party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 3:58 AM on Oct 12, 8 hours before the event, I fired away a note to
the class saying "This will probably be the last time most of us will
ever do something this crazy and fun. Enjoy the moment. Make your day.
Now go have the dance of your life."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That closing remark reflected the spirit and the motive for this flash
mob. Sloan class brings together experienced global leaders from more than 20
countries with more than 13 years of professional experiences on
average. Some classmates have commanded soldiers in battlefields, led
companies with thousands of employees, or formulated government policies
that affected millions of people. In classrooms we not only discuss
textbook cases, but also share our own stories. How can we make use of
such immense talents to put them into coherent action for a greater
cause and build something truly creative and unique for ourselves, for
GSB, or for Stanford?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flash mob, as wacky as it sounds, sets an interesting goal that none
of us has achieved before, and no one can achieve alone without
collaboration from others. It might sound goofy, but it'll certainly be
memorable. A group effort by definition, it requires intimidating level
of coordination, but it'll force us to see how far we're willing to
cooperate with each other and how well we can move in sync, literally
and figuratively. A flash mob pushes all of us out of comfort zone - no
matter how confident we are in formulating policies or how eloquent we
are in pitching strategies. A key element of leadership is to overcome
fear, especially fear from within. On Oct 12, no fear was greater than
the stage fry we had to endure for a span of 3:39.  Amazingly, every
part of the plan just played out to perfection. No one panicked, and
every one gave the absolute best individual dance performance ever. The
power of our vision unleashed the most hidden potential from us and
inspired us to deliver at the clutch moment when it mattered the most.
That's what A-players always do, and that's what Sloans do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Sloan fellows, it's been an honor to dance with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 17:55:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-11-12:from-gsb-reporter</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#30 - View from California</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/view-from-california</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight's speakers for &lt;a href="https://continuingstudies.stanford.edu/courses/course.php?cid=20121_POL+51"&gt;Election 2012&lt;/a&gt; talk "The View from California":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.stanford.edu/dept/president/biography/"&gt;Stanford University President John Hennessy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://eshoo.house.gov"&gt;Congresswoman Anna Eshoo (D-CA)&lt;/a&gt;, and Accel Partners' &lt;a href="http://www.accel.com/global/people/specialty/1/Theresia_Gouw"&gt;Theresia Gouw Ranzetta&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7458/13607755643_9e5567020f_c.jpg" width="800" height="305" alt="election"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Theresia) $2-3MM cost for complying with Sarbanes-Oxley Act for
    new IPO companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(John) whoever in the White House will face one of the worst budget
    deficit ever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;H1-B visa and &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DREAM_Act"&gt;DREAM Act&lt;/a&gt;
    was a big topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gouw was born in Indonesia, a first-generation American. I've seen a
    lot of excellent foreign-born English speakers and she has no accent
    whatsoever. Amazing. She's well covered by major news media, such as
    &lt;a href="http://www.forbes.com/lists/midas/2012/theresia-gouw-ranzetta.html"&gt;Forbes' Midas List of Tech Top Investors&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://business.time.com/2012/07/20/the-ten-most-influential-women-in-technology/slide/theresia-gouw-ranzetta/"&gt;Times's Top Ten Most Influential Women in Technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(John) For many years Silicon Valley has been blessed with staying
    far away from Washington DC. Not anymore. Technology invented out of
    Silicon Valley has wielded such a tremendous impact on the entire
    American society that Silicon Valley needs to champion its own cause
    with a stronger voice in DC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy Issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(John) privacy information in credit card transactions vs privacy
    issues from Internet use. Any difference? No much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(John) security issue is a much bigger issue than privacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(John) opt-in vs opt-out (US vs Europe)... opt-in is better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Anna) starting with children is easier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Theresia) it's a very technically complicated issue for the
    congress/DC to tackle effectively. The moment DC creates some
    legislation regarding technology issues such as privacy, it'll
    become obsolete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Theresia) the evolution of patent law is a much more complicated
    issue than privacy. it's much more difficult to deal with patent
    officers in the Valley.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Does Majority/Minority Work in the Congress?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Anna) if you are in the majority, be a senator as that's a very
    powerful position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Anna) tea party is bringing some insanity to science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Anna) ex-Speaker of the House Gingrich left his mark in the
    congress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nextca.org/topics/entry/initiative-process"&gt;&lt;em&gt;California's Initiative
Process&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(David) US' constitution has amended by 17 times; while California's
    consitution , 100+ years younger, has been amended by more than 500
    times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonderful talk. There were many topics I just couldn't fully digest yet.
Wish I had known more.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 10:01:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-10-31:view-from-california</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#25 - Summer Quarter Course Evaluation</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/summer-quarter-course-evaluation</link><description>&lt;p&gt;... continued from the explanation of &lt;a href="../../../2012/10/evaluate-course-with-CIDRAE/"&gt;CIDRAE Framework&lt;/a&gt;, here is the evaluation for the courses I took in the summer quarter of Stanford 2012-2013 in the Sloan Program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/summer-Q.png" width="800px" alt="Summer Quarter Score"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 22:14:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-10-18:summer-quarter-course-evaluation</guid><category>coassf</category></item><item><title>COASSF#01 - Survival Guide for the First Three Days</title><link>http://guizishanren.com/survival-guide-for-the-first-three-days</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For all the incoming Sloan Fellows of 2012-2013, the following items are
listed in descending order of pressing urgency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick up your &lt;em&gt;apartment keys&lt;/em&gt; from EV/Munger front desk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick up your &lt;em&gt;student ID&lt;/em&gt; from either Knight Management Center or
Student's Union, which is the main hub for all sorts of student
activities, close to Stanford Bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick up your &lt;em&gt;textbooks&lt;/em&gt; (five) from Sally at Knight Management
Center and say Hi to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check into your apartment,&lt;/em&gt; make sure keys, electricity, phone
and water work fine, and start writing down a list of what-to-buy for
the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a &lt;em&gt;local 650 phone number&lt;/em&gt;. Go to University Ave in Palo Alto
(this is like The Village in Beijing), as you can find both AT&amp;amp;T and
Verizon stores here within walking distance. I think you can apply
Stanford's student discount only on a two-year contract so be careful of
what you sign up for (iPhone5 is rumored to come out in this fall).
Stanford's area code is 650 so make sure this is the one you get(this is
what we're here for right?), and not some codes from totally-uncool
suburban areas. Also be aware that SMS text is not a necessity in US
(depending who you ask). A lot of Americans don't do SMS. My package
doesn't include a quota for text message so I'll be charged 25c for
every text message and I'm fine with that. My wife and I have a family
plan from AT&amp;amp;T and our combined monthly cost is about \$150. My data
quota is 3GB -it should be sufficient as we can ride on Stanford wi-fi
on campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parking on University Ave&lt;/em&gt; is not difficult at all. There is a
parking tower located on the northwest corner of University Ave and
Bryant St. It's free for the first three hours (quite a deal considering
how difficult it is to park in the street). I can always find available
parking here without fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SMS text&lt;/em&gt; is a very outdated technology, no better than VCD. I
suggest we all use WeChat(微信) from Tencent(腾讯) to communicate. It's
superior to traditional SMS in every way. It's available on both iOS and
Android, but not on Blackberry (pls, for the love of God, throw away
your BB if you haven't already done so. BB belongs to museums). For non-Chinese, go with either whatsapp or
Kik or iMessage or a gazillion of other choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get through &lt;em&gt;the first night&lt;/em&gt;, you need: 1) pillow, 2) quilt,
3) bed sheet. The easy solution is to visit IKEA in nearby Palo Alto and
get it done. For more details on the shopping guide, read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have a car/rental car now, you'll need to buy &lt;em&gt;parking
permit&lt;/em&gt; from Stanford's Department of Transportation and Parking so
that you can park your car in EV. It's not open on weekends so do it the
first thing in the morning on Monday. They only sell "summer quarter"
permit through September (the end of current academic year) for \$75. In
August they'll start selling \$300/year parking permit for the new
academic year. Our parking permit is of type RS (for residents).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Get online&lt;/em&gt;. Go to &lt;a href="http://rescomp.stanford.edu/"&gt;http://rescomp.stanford.edu/&lt;/a&gt; to register
all your devices that need to have Internet connection, including
desktop/laptop/iPad/phone/AppleTV/PS3/Xbox. You'll get on the wi-fi
network "Stanford Residence". It's fast and reliable, good enough to
watch streaming movie without a hiccup. If you have a router, you can
also establish your own wi-fi network for yourself (a good thing to do).
Be aware that even with your own in-room wi-fi network up and running,
you still need to register all your devices onto Stanford's network
(this is for your own security protection). Between my wife and me we
have at least ten devices that need to be registered. For the best help
on IT, besides me you can also ask for help from RCC (resident computing
consultant), who is also a student in the residence and trained to take
care of all your computing needs. You can find out who is your RCC from
rescomp website. Another trick to note: you can use one registered
device to register another device which doesn't have a web UI. For
example, you have a laptop that's already registered, but want to get
your AppleTV registered as well. Note down the ethernet address of your
AppleTV, login to rescomp using your laptop, and indicate that you're
registering ANOTHER device, put down the ethernet ID of your AppleTV,
and get it registered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buy/lease a car&lt;/em&gt; You can buy a new car (most expensive but
entirely risk free), buy a used car from private parties (easiest  but a
lot of risks), buy certified pre-owned cars from auto dealers (cheaper
than buying a new car with minimum risk), or lease a car from rental-car
companies. I don't know much about leasing, but I'd suggest buying
certified pre-owned (CPO) cars from dealers. The process is very simple,
visit an auto-dealer, test-drive, make payments, get auto-insurance on
the spot, and drive the car away - all can be done in one day. Large
dealers (you can find the authentic auto dealers from the brand's
official website, such as www.audi.com） all have their own websites
which list real-time car-lot inventory. Buying a car in an auto dealer
is one of the most intimidating experiences in America so have fun with
all the usual sales tricks. Note that bluetooch connection can be very
handy here as it's illegal to hold your phone while driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Buy auto-insurance&lt;/em&gt;. Without auto insurance, you cannot drive on
the road in US. You can totally buy auto insurance with driver's license from
Beijing/Shanghai or an international driver's license. The sales guy at
auto dealer will call upon an insurance agent during closing to help you
with all the paperwork (which might take as long as an hour). Before
going to the auto dealer, you can get a quotation from GEICO.com
(Buffett's favorite business, America's best online auto-insurance
company) to get a benchmark  figure (it's a function of your demographic
profile and the kind of car you'll buy). I'm paying roughly \$400-500
for six-month in a month-by-month plan (ie. I can switch to other
insurance plans any time with no penalty).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parking on campus&lt;/em&gt;. During summer time, most if not all the
parking lots on campus are free after 4pm so take advantage of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eating&lt;/em&gt;. For breakfast, I'd suggest you buy a microwave oven to
take care of that. For lunch, there are many avenues available for lunch
on campus, like the cafeteria in Knight Management Center, Stanford Coho
below Student's Union, Munger's famous pizza place, and Arrillaga Family
Dining Commons. You can use credit card and student ID to buy meal plans
(for details on meal plans, check out Stanford's website) in Arrillaga,
which is the only one open during summer quarter. I bought a five-meal
lunch package from Arrillaga. For dinner, other than those places on
campus, the usual places are: 1) University Ave in Palo Alto (trendy);
2) Town &amp;amp; Country Village in Palo Alto (cozy with many varieties); 3)
Mountain view (right next to EV). There are some Chinese restaurants
along El Camino Real and many more in the nearby Mountain View.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer&lt;/em&gt;. I'm a notorious Mac Evangelist (which is way, way
beyond the realm of merely fan boys) so be afraid, be very afraid. Based on
what I've seen around campus in the last few days, it's evident to me
that it must be illegal to use non-Mac laptops in Stanford. An MBA
(Macbook Air) will suffice our study needs. Macbook Pro is too heavy
(unless you want to get the retina display). For Mac users, get Office
2011 for Mac. It's fully compatible with the windows version and you can
buy it with deep discount as a student. There is an Apple Store in
Stanford Shopping Mall as well as University Ave. We can use student
discount when buying MBA but it's really not that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shopping&lt;/em&gt;. Two convenience stores/minimart, CVS and Walgreens
are your friends for daily simple stuff. There is an CVS on El Camino
Real in Mountain View that is open 24/7, within five minute driving
distance from EV. If you want to do a grand slam of all the
furniture/home necessities with serviceable quality,  hit IKEA in east
Palo Alto. For anything in electronics, go to the world-famous Fry's in
Palo Alto (it's huge) or Mountain View. For reasonable quality
department store, go to Target close to El Camino Real in Mountain View.
For good quality grocery, go to Trader Joe's in Town &amp;amp; Country Village
in Palo Alto. For Asian-themed all-in-one grocery, go to Ranch 99
Supermarket  in Mountain View. For late-night shopping spree, go to
Safeway in Mountain View along El Camino Real that is open for 24 hours.
Stanford Shopping Mall at the start of the legendary Sand Hill Road is
home to some fairly up-scaled shops and stores with very limited dining
options. Google Map is reasonably accurate in US but not 100%.
Double-check with Yelp (which is usually reliable with local info and
user reviews) to confirm direction/store hours/etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;em&gt;Euro2012&lt;/em&gt;. Off-campus, Hooters is a reliable bet, or you
can just go to the usual suspect University Ave, where you can find many
bars with screens. On campus, both Arrillaga and Coho have several big
screens and bar tenders at Coho won't kick you out if you just sit there
being a cheap student watching games drooling at C.Ronaldo  or
Balotelli without buying anything. To secure a table at Coho, arrive at
least one hour before the Final.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Golf&lt;/em&gt;. If at one point ever in your life you might be thinking
about starting in golf, now is the time and this is THE place.
Stanford's self-owned golf course offers incredible discount to
staff/students at only \$25! The green fee is so cheap it will be a
serious crime Not to brush up your golf skill here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communication&lt;/em&gt;. Besides using WeChat to replace SMS, Skype is a
good alternative to traditional telephone. Skype is available on wi-fi,
which means we can possibly use Skype in place of phone. My Skype ID:
herbertyang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stanford Dish Trail&lt;/em&gt;. A hidden gem in Stanford, a two-mile loop
trail with paranormal view of Stanford, Palo Alto and Mountain View, the
best place for a walk in the last ray of light at dusk with utmost
tranquility.  There is no parking lot for this park. Park your car along
Stanford Ave leading to its south entrance and don't mess up our
distinguished faculty professors' backyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voila!&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Herbert Yang</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 22:10:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-06-29:survival-guide-for-the-first-three-days</guid><category>coassf</category></item></channel></rss>