<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/business.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://guizishanren.com/</id><updated>2014-11-04T08:00:00-08:00</updated><entry><title>Reid Hoffman from How To Start A Startup Series</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/reid-hoffman-YC-startup-series" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-11-04T08:00:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-11-04:reid-hoffman-YC-startup-series</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Series: How To Start a Startup by Y Combinator, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaker: &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/reidhoffman"&gt;Reid Hoffman&lt;/a&gt;, founder of Linkedin, partner of Greylock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avenue: NVIDIA Auditorium, Stanford University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic:  How to be a Great Founder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't do notes from page to page. I just jotted down what was most useful to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How did you hang in there in the tough time of Linkedin?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(context: Linkedin was a distant #2 behind all the major social network darlings from Friendster, Myspace, and Facebook, for a very long period)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a strong vision into the future (the separation of one's social and professional online identity/community) and knowing my company is always closer to that vision than anybody else really helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to judge a good founding team?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a good founding team, cofounders just work really well together. They help each other navigate through unchartered waters and figure out the truth or the missing piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;How to ensure the cofounder is the right person?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a series of very robust and wide-ranging conversations in life that exhaust all the topics, so that no stone is left untouched and all the parameters, no matter how extreme they are, have been explored. Having those hard soul-searching conversations upfront rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Life of a founder&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Startup founders have no balance of life. Period. (ok, at least for a period of time when product is launched)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>罗生门演义-陈欧版</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/about-chen-ou-startup-past" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-12T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-06-12:about-chen-ou-startup-past</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;本来已经懒得再看创业公司的恩怨情仇了，但这几天关于聚美优品陈欧的文章太多，各种骂战，各种狗血内幕层出不穷，连&lt;a href="http://www.thev.net/"&gt;九瓜&lt;/a&gt;都问我对此事的看法。我就把两篇对立的文章都看了一遍。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我也来自斯坦福商学院，陈欧是2010届的MBA，我是2013届的&lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/programs/msx"&gt;Sloan Fellow&lt;/a&gt;；我跟陈欧应该也算新加坡的校友，我是新加坡教育部奖学金计划的第三批学生，在新加坡国立大学毕业，陈欧是南阳理工大学的，是。。。批的，不管了，反正是我离开新加坡以后的师弟了。我并不认识陈欧，也没想在这个论战里站在哪一方，我以前没有看过关于陈欧的访谈，对于此事也仅仅看过如下两篇泣血长文。但我觉得大家的争议如此之多，不免好奇，于是就想看看，这这个扑朔迷离的罗生门里，如果是Jack Ryan这样的分析师，会得出什么样的结论呢？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;反方嘉宾：一个貌似做VC的人最初的所谓爆料：&lt;a href="http://weibo.com/1617902267/B8pGMuJut"&gt;JMYP的C公子那些事儿&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;正方嘉宾：陈欧的联合创始人刘辉： &lt;a href="http://weibo.com/1885454921/B8Iwflu8F"&gt;我和“Forrest Li”不得不说的故事&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;看完了以后，我觉得是酱紫的：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在关键历史事件的回顾上，刘辉和爆料方其实没有本质的冲突和不一致。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爆料方显然动机不纯，明显要黑陈欧。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;刘辉义愤填膺，是个好哥们儿，但是他的陈述过于感情用事，而且暴露出自己显然不在公司的核心决策层面。絮絮叨叨地提供了很多无关紧要的细节，对陈欧的帮助其实不大。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下几点是可以推测成立的事实：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陈欧是斯坦福商学院的MBA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这一点无需争论，确是事实。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;能考上斯坦福MBA还是一件很牛逼的事情。我见过的斯坦福中国MBA，整体非常优秀，我在他们这个年纪的见识和技能均不如现在的他们。我在2013和2014届里的熟人多一些。虽然并不认识所有的华人MBA，但基本上在认识的人当中，没有一个让我心里嘀咕“这人这么跑到斯坦福来了”，大家都有各自优秀的地方。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GG早期版本的代码是陈欧写出来的&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;虽然这个版本的确很烂，但这一点双方都无异议。烂归烂，始编码者为陈欧。陈欧以前不会编码，也是事实。作为一个没有经过科班CS培训的人，自己吭哧吭哧地专研C花了几个月时间写了个游戏平台，这份毅力和决心是很难得的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陈欧赴斯坦福一事本身不能说明什么问题&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;申请斯坦福MBA通常需要起码一年的时间，陈欧2007年初收到offer，应该最晚从2006年的秋天就开始申请了。从Forrest的角度，联合创始人要抛下公司业务去美国念两年书，显然不是一件很爽的事，心有不满可以理解。但是否能因为此事就说陈欧做得不对，过河拆桥云云，倒也未必。这完全取决联合创始人之间的Founder's Agreement是如何约定的，股东如何退出，等等。如果在协议上没有约束的话，陈欧想干嘛就干嘛，未必需要从道德层面对他上纲上线。如果我是Forrest，会让陈欧在赴美之前就放弃公司的股权，因为陈欧去美国之后显然已经无法全职履行GG公司的职责，无法对投资人负责。Forrest当初没这么做，是他自己的商业决定，也无所谓对错。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陈欧和Forrest都是GG公司的联合创始人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;难怪这件事会吵得沸沸扬扬，因为这样的事情按照硅谷的行规几乎不大可能发生。创始人和联合创始人，虽然只有两个字的差别，但衍生了硅谷无数狗血剧情，完胜好莱坞顶级编剧的想象力，最煽情的近期大片请见纽约时报的专栏记者Nick Bilton的巨著&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Hatching-Twitter-Nick-Bilton-ebook/dp/B00CDUVSQ0/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1402643331&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=twitter+book"&gt;《Hatching Twitter: A True Story of Money, Power, Friendship, and Betrayal》&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个事情其实很简单，从技术上说，GG一开始是注册在陈欧名下的，所以陈欧是当然的“创始人”。但后来陈欧把30%的股权分给了Forrest也是事实，陈欧同意给Forrest“联合创始人”的头衔也是事实。如何判定一个创业者是否为万众瞩目的“联合创始人”在硅谷并没有一个绝对的标准，这是一个比较虚幻（但让人魂牵梦萦）的概念。&lt;em&gt;唯一的标准就是看其他的联合创始人是否反对你使用这个头衔，只要大家都默认，你就是联合创始人&lt;/em&gt;（当然股权得起码在15-20%以上，而且你需要是全职，否则你作为小股东迟早会被大股东虐得体无完肤）。一个人加入公司的时间，承担的职责，出资金额，能力的高下，这都不是决定他/她是否是“联合创始人”的关键性因素。起码在某一个时间段，陈欧是默认Forrest联合创始人的资格的，而且Forrest本身又是全职CEO，亮出联合创始人的头衔很合理。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这件事情让大众不忿的地方在于Forrest是在GG公司成立两年以后才加入的，所以刘辉和陈欧在事后会觉得因此Forrest不能叫自己公司的联合创始人。他们心有不甘可以理解 - 在硅谷正常情况下很少有人会在公司成立了两年以后割让出30%的股权给一个新来的人。但早知如此，又何必当初？如果觉得Forrest能力不济，当初就不要给他这个头衔呗。既然同意了Forrest的加入，又跟Forrest一起以联合创始人的阵营见投资人，在那段时间，Forrest的确可以自己号称是公司的联合创始人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;至于刘辉特别不爽的Forrest后来执行的“去陈欧化”，无非是公司内部政治斗争而已，在每家公司都在上演，无所谓对与错。如果我是Forrest，也会把一走了之的联合创始人的手下团队彻底清洗掉，这是一个CEO工作手册里的第一页内容。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陈欧在聚美优品以前是否有成功的创业史&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VC人的意思是，陈欧把自己35%的股权卖了70万美元本身不足以证明他“有成功的创业史”，这个我倒觉得过于苛刻了。一个24岁的年轻人，白手起家搞了家公司挣了70万美金，虽然不是一个可以退休养老的光辉退出，但也还不错了。值不值得大书特书地炫耀是一回事，但起码初次创业没有输掉裤子就很不容易了。在开会时说一句“我是一个成功的创业者”不是什么犯罪。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GG公司的前身发展不成功&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这也是事实。10000玩家的游戏平台，算不上什么了不得的业绩，或许以后可以有发展，但陈欧自己走掉了，所以GG公司的前身断代史到此为止，从双方的描述上（包括刘辉）看不来在那个时间点GG是一个多么成功的企业。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我没看过陈欧的访谈，不知道他自己是如何描述GG公司前身的发展的。这件事情上的争议在我看来没有什么意义，毕竟他在四年之内搞了家美国上市公司出来，这总不是假的吧？英雄莫问出处。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GG公司后来的成功发展跟陈欧没有关系&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GG转型后的成功，首要的功劳当然是CEO Forrest了，谁叫他是CEO呢？那时显然跟陈欧已经没有关系了。刘辉在这件事情上的分析显然流于情绪化，纯粹属于公司内部业务方向讨论的陈年芝麻谷子烂史，不能说明任何问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;至于刘辉对Forrest义愤填膺的各种指责，纯粹是一家之言的愤激之言，没什么实质价值。创业公司到了后来，哪家不都是联合创始人互相骂街的？没有拳脚相向就算不错的了。Welcome to the startup club。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;陈欧是一个牛逼的游戏玩家&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我自己是一个十年的魔兽世界玩家，从2004年11月23号魔兽世界首发就开始玩美服，中间一直断断续续，属于骨灰级别的菜鸟玩家，跟陈欧这种惊才绝艳的超级大高手不能比。陈欧在魔兽世界所向睥睨，应该也是事实。一个在魔兽世界里超一流的玩家在智商和领导力上都不会是泛泛之辈。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;不过，牛逼的玩家，并不等同于牛逼的程序员，更加不等同于成功的企业家。这段经历，是一个有趣的注脚，仅此而已。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后，在这场唾沫横飞的口水仗里，有一个众人都默认的不言而喻的假设，所有的义愤，不管是正方还是反方，都基于这个假设。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个假设就是，一个事业成功的人，他应该同时也占据道德的制高点，是一个在道德和道义上都经得起考验的人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;而这个假设，在实际生活中，显然是不成立的。&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="中文"></category></entry><entry><title>Analysis of 2014 US Summer Tentpole Movie Release Schedule</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/2014-US-summer-tentpole-schedule" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-24T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-05-24:2014-US-summer-tentpole-schedule</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's my annual analysis of US summer tentpole movie release schedule. The 2013 one is &lt;a href="../2013-US-summer-tentpole-schedule/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14261438535" title="2014 Summer Release Schedule by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5531/14261438535_51ff7d4218_o.png" width="783" height="1126" alt="2014 Summer Release Schedule"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, 2014 is really not that exciting for US summer movie market. Most of the tentpole releases feel like cover bands to warm up the stage for the real headliners like The Rolling Stones. With "Avengers 2", "Star Wars", "Fast &amp;amp; Furious 7", "Mission Impossible 5", "Jurassic Park", "Mad Max", 2015 is poised to be a banner year for Hollywood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most remarkable phenomenon in 2014 summer schedule is that Captain America chose to open on April 4, a full month ahead of the official summer season. It's become a monster hit and that will probably change the landscape for next year and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boredom of this summer can be seen from the fact that there are 3 horror wide releases in the summer. Is Hollywood running out of mindless action blockbusters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The release schedule suggests that "Transformers 3" is the only "event movie" that is expected to suck up the entire market demand for that frame. Nobody dares to come close to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, action-comedy is the most frequent combo (duh...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every other week studios throw family-themed animation flicks into
    the mix to keep the kids interested, so that their parents can earn
    some "chips" to go to cinema next week without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Johnny Depp has officially become a box-office poison when he's not Cap. Jack Sparrow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might see the last big-production movie from the Wachowskis after "Jupiter Ascending". If it fails (most likely it will), no studio executives would want to ever write a check to Wachowskis again. Mila Kunis, seriously?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Analysis of 2013 US Summer Tentpole Movie Release Schedule</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/2013-US-summer-tentpole-schedule" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-02T14:06:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-06-02:2013-US-summer-tentpole-schedule</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I was actively procrastinating on one of the final papers for the
quarter, I did what I do most naturally - checking out movies. When I
was in China during the past five years, one of the things I missed the
most about America was its summer time, when exciting tentpole event
movies came out one after another, one-upping each other
on box-office records. It's the quintessential  American cultural
immersion experience. At times of feeling down in January - April, I
would cheer myself up by thinking, it's OK, the summer is coming, there
will be many great movies to watch and plenty fantasies to live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite of my intimate knowledge of US box-office and movie release
schedule, I have never studied its distribution in an analytical fashion
- until now. For Hollywood's major movie studios, there is a whole
science about staking your flag on the most coveted weekends and scaring
away competitors, though many times they do have to learn to cohabit.
It's a very interesting chess game where game theory and various tactics
are played to the fullest. Here's a simple analysis of all the
wide-release (more than 3,000 cinemas) movies for 2013 summer season by
genres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14281436883" title="2013 Summer Wide-Release Schedule by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3825/14281436883_f45d030967_c.jpg" width="616" height="800" alt="2013 Summer Wide-Release Schedule"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few observations and takeaways, some of which must be
obvious to industry veterans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule #1, balance, balance, balance. Always balance the mix. Never
    over-saturate screens with one single genre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any deviation from Rule #1 spells trouble. For example, Will Smith
    (After Earth) is on the way of losing its opening weekend box-office
    champion title to Now You See Me, which will raise some eyebrows. I
    think Smith was a bit over-confident of his box-office draw. R.I.P.D
    and RED2 on July 19 are both cross-over between action and comedy,
    which is kinda a rare phenomenon. It might just work well for both.
    Matt Damon's Elysium is pitted against Percy Jackson, which targets
    slightly younger audience but will still bring considerable
    challenge to Damon. Maybe Elysium's distributor TriStar just doesn't
    have enough confidence in this movie to stake it in a more
    competitive weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically speaking, there are only two event movies for this
    summer: Iron Man 3 and Star Trek, both of which are well-established
    sci-fi franchises. When they opened, every other studio stayed away
    to avoid being burned alive. Iron Man 3 has lived up to industry
    expectation while not so much for Star Trek (though personally I
    like it a lot).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Action-comedy is the most frequent combo (duh...). "Action" includes
    action, adventure, thriller, sci-fi, fantasy, basically pop-corn
    movies that do not exhaust too much brain power, movies that can
    help you just "let go".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every other week studios throw family-themed animation flicks into
    the mix to keep the kids interested, so that their parents can earn
    some "chips" to go to cinema next week without them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Horror movie is just not for summer time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wide-release drama is a hard-sell. It takes some gravy ingredients
    like Fitzgerald and DiCaprio to open a serious drama movie. Most
    other drama movies (Before Midnight) in the summer are just opening
    bands to the major headliner rock superstars (action/comedy), from a
    commercial standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three weekends with 3-4 wide-release movies. May 24 is the
    memorial day weekend, when Hollywood has the highest
    single-day box-office gross for the entire year. I'm not quite sure
    what's going on with July 19 and Aug 9. They look like dumping
    ground to me, or maybe studios just try to screw up each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distribution-wise, Pitt's World War Z and Depp's Lone Ranger have
    both been set up to perform (with only one animation to hold hands
    with on their opening weekends). If they fail, well, then they're
    meant to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Redesign Business Model of Animation Films</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/redesign-business-model-of-animation-films" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-13T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-05-13:redesign-business-model-of-animation-films</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In February 2013, &lt;a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/jeffrey-katzenberg-dreamworks-animations-very-424699"&gt;DreamWorks Animation, the maker of highly successful franchises of “Shrek” and “Madagascar”, laid off 350 of its 2,200 employees&lt;/a&gt;. The restructuring was driven by disappointing results of &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1446192/?ref_=fn_al_tt_1"&gt;Rise of the Guardians&lt;/a&gt;, which forced the studio to take $87 Million charge. The shocking news begs the question: what’s wrong with DreamWorks Animation Studio, or what’s wrong with animation film business in general? Animation film business has always been a hit-driven model. What happens when the streak ends and a hit becomes a dud?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animation film industry has had a great run in the last 20 years. Pixar’s cultural phenomenon Toy Story (1995) marked the arrival of 3D animation. Since then several specialized animation studios have emerged and become dominant players in this space, such as Pixar, DreamWorks Animation, and Blue Sky (Fox). They have created some of the most recognized global brands from Hollywood, such as Toy Story, Shrek, Madagascar, Kung Fu Panda, and Ice Age. Pixar’s unbelievable streak of 13 hits in a row has become the stuff of legend not only in Hollywood, but also in the entire business world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in recent years this once highly lucrative business seems to show some &lt;strong&gt;strains in its growth&lt;/strong&gt;. Pixar’s Cars 2 (2011) was considered by most an artistic failure and Brave (2012) received lukewarm response from critics. Some CG service providers, like Digital Domain, almost went bankruptcy. Then came the news of the DreamWorks Animation’s massive layoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An analysis into the two leading animation studios, Pixar and DreamWorks Animation seems to suggest that the true financial return on major animation studios is not as stellar as it seems, once escalating production budget and prolonged development cycle are taken into consideration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14548395755" title="Exhibit 1_Pixar by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3910/14548395755_5ca49a8f3c_z.jpg" width="640" height="405" alt="Exhibit 1_Pixar"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 1 lists all the 13 Pixar movies with their reported production budgets. Since the first Toy Story (1995), which was made with only $30 Million, Pixar has been spending more and more on every subsequent film. The most recent five movies all carry a budget of north of $180 Million. Granted, they are all huge moneymakers, raking in receipts ranging from $500 Million to over $1 Billion (Toy Story 3). The worldwide total box-office numbers are summarized in Appendix 1. If we measure financial return in terms of &lt;em&gt;Gross/Budget&lt;/em&gt;, the calculation shows that most Pixar movies had a multiple between 2.8X (Car 2) and 12.1X (Toy Story). Is this good enough? Not really if we keep peeling off the onion. Wikipedia provides some useful information on the development cycle of all the Pixar movies3, which shows that most of them took 4 – 6 years4 to complete (Appendix 1). Given the “investment horizon” and “total return multiple”, we can actually calculate the implied annualized IRR (Internal Rate of Return) for these movies, as indicated on Exhibit 1. The chart shows that the return for more recent Pixar movies are hovering around 25% - 30% on annual basis, and it seems to be on a downward trend lately. Pixar’s earlier movies, though produced with much smaller budgets, actually yielded much higher IRRs. If we use Silicon Valley’s VC investment as a benchmark, IRR of 25-30% is decent, but hardly earth shattering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14544997581" title="Exhibit 2_SKG by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5554/14544997581_583835a27d_z.jpg" width="640" height="333" alt="Exhibit 2_SKG"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same analysis on Pixar’s main competitor DreamWorks Animation points to similar trends and interesting facts, as seen on Exhibit 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production budget for major animation films keeps increasing. The most recent 14 movies all carry a price tag of at least $130 Millions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DreamWorks Animation’s performance is less consistent than Pixar’s. Occasionally it had a super achiever such as Shrek that had 8.1X multiple, but most recent films had multiples roughly between 1.2X and 5.1X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wonder DreamWorks is so vulnerable to one movie’s failure – because it doesn’t really make that much extra profit in general. Nowadays major animation movies often require $80 - $100 Millions in marketing. After splitting 50-50 with exhibitors, a movie that makes $300 Millions in worldwide gross receipt does not have much left to cover the marketing expense for the producing studio, as in the case of Rise of the
Guardians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14525309636" title="Exhibit 3_market by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3913/14525309636_e0442121b2_z.jpg" width="640" height="392" alt="Exhibit 3_market"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it’s becoming increasingly more expensive and taking longer to produce high-quality, profitable animation films in Hollywood, an emerging market on the other side of the Pacific Ocean just can’t get enough movies of any kind in general. As Exhibit 3 shows, China’s movie market has been growing explosively in recent years. It just surpassed Japan in 2012 to become the second largest film market behind US with $2.7 Billions in gross box-office. Its annual growth rate in the past four years has been at least 20% and as high as 140%6. During the same time, US’ box-office was trickling up and down around $10 Billions, with at most a nominal grow rate of 6.5% (2012). Global consulting firm E&amp;amp;Y in its Spotlight on China 2012 report predicted that by year 2020 China will overtake US to become the world’s No.1 movie market. My back-of-the-envelop calculation confirms this is not an outlandish claim. Based on 2012 numbers, if we assume China will grow at 25% annually (which is very conservative, considering the recent streak of record-breaking events in China) and US will grow 5% (which could be too optimistic), China’s gross box-office receipt will reach $16.1 Billions in 2020, edging
US out of the top position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14361801928" title="Exhibit 4_screens by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5561/14361801928_852ab47978_z.jpg" width="640" height="363" alt="Exhibit 4_screens"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we have enough reasons to believe China’s film industry will indeed sustain its current high growth rate? Some further comparison across major movie markets that on key indicators can reasonably justify this assumption. Exhibit 4 compares number of screens per million people. US is leading the world with 126.9 screens per million people; most of the western countries are in the range of 50 – 90; China’s Asian neighbors Japan and South Korea are between 25 – 40. China only has 9.7 screens, less than 10% of US7. While it’s debatable which country is the best benchmark of China, China will probably share a lot more in common with US with its population size, population dispersion, and geography. By US standard, China’s number of screens will have substantial room to scale up in the coming years, which will become a key driver to spur box-office growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14361801958" title="Exhibit 5_Admission by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2933/14361801958_0aa24f10d5_z.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Exhibit 5_Admission"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another comparison on admission per capita also supports the growth prospect of China’s movie market. Exhibit 5 shows this statistic across major film markets based on 2011 numbers. China’s admission capita was only 0.54, almost one- tenth of that of US (4.15). As China’s
GDP grows, Chinese consumers will shift their focus from basic daily needs (food and housing) to more intellectually and emotionally enlightening activities such as watching movies. The government is also pouring more resources and capital into cultural industries as part of its “12th Five-Year Central Plan”. Therefore it is reasonable to expect Chinese consumers will exhibit similar cinema-watching behaviors as those in US and other western countries in years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite of the rosy outlook of China’s film market, Hollywood’s studios are having a hard time taking full advantage of the situation because foreign-produced films are subject to a quota system that the Chinese government has imposed. Every year only 34 foreign-produced movies can be released into China’s cinemas, and that covers not just US, but also European countries. The 34 movies include all genres like sci-fi, live-action, romantic comedy and drama. Usually only few of them are animation movies. So out of all the animation movies Hollywood has in a year (27, according to IMDB) that are expensively produced and craving for more box- office, only a few most well-known ones can tap into China’s vast market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the problem we have seen at a macro level, is a business model in Hollywood that is too hit-driven, getting too expensive and financially risky; at the same time, China’s fast-growing film market can’t get enough share of good quality animation films from Hollywood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This situation calls for a creative solution that can turn a traditional hit-driven business model into a growth-driven business model with potential of hits. There are four key elements to this solution, code-named “New Co”  for the sake of discussion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, New Co should make animation feature films with budget of &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; Millions instead of $150 Millions. Exhibit 6 provides breakdowns of a typical production budget for animation films between independent studios (New Co) and established major studios (Pixar, DreamWorks). Most of the production costs goes into animation, which includes art design, modeling, surfacing/texturing, grooming, rigging, etc. If New Co sets up its production/rendering team in China, it will be able to take advantage of the cheaper labor costs there and deliver the same
effects with much lower budget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14546853084" title="Exhibit 6_Indie_vs_studio by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3877/14546853084_f43fb79063_z.jpg" width="640" height="360" alt="Exhibit 6_Indie_vs_studio"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, New Co should shorten the development cycle from the typical 4 – 6 years to &lt;strong&gt;18 – 24 months&lt;/strong&gt;. Established studios like Pixar and DreamWorks sometimes can get trapped in the perfectionist mentality and become a victim of their own past success. While that seems to be the norm of the industry, I think it is possible to avoid that by creating a new studio like New Co with no such legacy culture but execution-focused disciplines from day one. In the world of artist creation, it can be difficult to balance enhanced artist expression and marginal effort. Having said that, there are certain lessons New Co can learn from the past to embark on a light journey. For example, do not overkill on furs, which consumes way too much design labor and computing power. Also, let good story carry the movie, not the technical representation of the animation. Story should always be the most critical element of any successful movies, including animation ones. A studio culture can be built from day one so that animators don’t get too carried away with the movie’s technical achievement while scriptwriters have a stronger voice in the development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, New Co should aim to do wide-release (over 3,000 cinemas in US) of its movies in &lt;strong&gt;both China and US&lt;/strong&gt; to fully tap into the market potential of these two countries. It can achieve this by setting up legal entity in China and position its China entity as a local studio producer so that its movies will not be subject to the annual quota of 34 foreign movies. At the same time its US entity will work with US distributors to release the same movie. Pleasant Sheep series is currently the most successful animation film franchise in China, even though its production quality and artistic appeal is appalling compared to those from Hollywood. Despite of its low-bar quality, it has been able to pull in impressive box-office numbers ($25 Million) year after year with each sequel, as Exhibit 8 shows. On a cost per minute basis, Pleasant Sheep is only $12 Thousands compared to $1.6 Million of a typical Pixar film, but its profit margin (measured by box-office divided by production cost) is 25X compared to Pixar film’s 3.3X. I believe there is room for New Co to arbitrage between high-end Pixar films and low-end Pleasant Sheep, where New Co can produce a decent quality animation film with only one-tenth of the cost of a Pixar film while enjoying a much higher financial return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exhibit 8: Cost, Return, and Production Comparison For Three Tiers of Players&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Studio&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Cost/Minute&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Budget&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Boxoffice&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Margin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Creative Team Location&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Production&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pleasant Sheep&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$12 K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼$1 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼$25 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼25x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼New Co&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼$166 K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼$15 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼$150 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼10x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼Hollywood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼China&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼Pixar Studio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼$1,666 K&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼$150 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼$500 MM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼3.3x&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Hollywood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼Hollywood&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last but not the least, New Co should assemble a global operation with the
best talents from Hollywood and China and enable them to do what they can do best. Hollywood’s creative talents (directors, writers, animators and producers) are still the best in the world and they should still be the driving force of the animation movie production. China’s production quality for CG effects has been rising steadily over the years and there are abundant talents for low-to-mid range art designers and illustrators. China’s computing power, electricity utility, and labor all have significant cost advantages over Hollywood. New Co should leverage the best resources from both China and Hollywood and create a global process that enables open communication and smooth collaboration among branch offices that are geographically dispersed. Such global collaboration is certainly a challenge for any team, but that’s where the industry is going and sooner or later existing players and new entrants all have to adapt to this new way of artistic creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14528186546" title="Exhibit 9_competitor by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3869/14528186546_209114506c_z.jpg" width="640" height="588" alt="Exhibit 9_competitor"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up the proposed solution, by pivoting a new animation film studio like New Co in China for production and Hollywood for creativity, it is possible to turn the traditional hit-driven business model into a growth model with tremendous opportunities of hits. It will be a much more appealing model to the investors and enable animation film makers to develop high-quality films in larger quantity, shorter cycle, and lower budget. It’ll be a multi-win scenario for the market, for the investors, and for the filmmakers. (Exhibit 9 displays the relationships among the major groups of players in this space.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The End&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#41 - Why Search Funds Might Make Sense</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/why-search-funds-make-sense" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-24T16:07:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-01-24:why-search-funds-make-sense</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some Stanford lecturers and alumni are involved in the business of
search fund, but this is one type of investment vehicle that is often
not well understood by people from outside. The model makes sense to the
three parties involved in the following ways ... I think:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the searchers&lt;/em&gt; (MBAs in pair, who go raising capital to fund the
search, identify an acquisition target company, raise more capital to
buy it, run it for several years, and sell it for profit at the right
EBIDTA),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This model is almost exclusively for MBAs (mostly young) with little
    to no operating/management experience but have some entrepreneurial
    spirit to be a change agent and live their lives on their own terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It fits with newly minted MBAs' desire of running businesses,
    improving operation and managing processes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many MBAs (especially those with consulting or banking background)
    have no particular desire for product creation/development, nor
    strong passion for any particular domains, but want to run a
    business by applying business school tactics and skills. Search
    fund's model suits such desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It provides to the searchers the opportunity to become CEO of a
    small to medium-sized company (right away after the search is
    completed and the deal is closed), which is not available to most
    MBA graduates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The searchers have the luxury of learning the business at reasonable
    pace and groom themselves into effective CEOs because search fund
    targets are usually cash flow positive business with stable business
    models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The searchers don't have to deal with the nuances faced by the CEO
    of a typical startup, like handling all the back room matters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a possibility that it could be relatively easy to turn
    around a small-sized traditional type of business that doesn't
    typically embrace modern management practice such as regular team
    meetings or neat financial analysis from Excel. There might be many
    low-hanging fruits there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the investors&lt;/em&gt; (individuals who give capital to the searchers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower risk (lower return as well) because the target companies
    already have EBIDTA and a stable operating structure and
    environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower entry of investment compared to VC and PE funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contrarian play because most of the target companies are in
    traditional, less sexy industries (but with potential to unlock
    value from simple process improvement) that are often overlooked by
    the VC/PE firms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lower risk from more flexibility in capital commitment due to the
    two-staged funding process and the usual right-of-the-first-refusal
    clause.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to get much more involvement and utilize his/her own domain
    expertise, unlike being a LP in a typical VC/PE fund.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better access to the invested target companies because GP =
    Management team, which provides a higher level of comfort and lowers
    the perceived risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the sellers&lt;/em&gt; (current owners of the target company who sell the
company to the search fund)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search funds might be the only buyers available as their companies
    are usually fairly small, under the radar screen of the big VC/PE
    firms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suits the needs for the owners/founders who want to retire but want
    to make sure the business is in good hands as search fund GPs are
    much more committed than typical VC professionals, who are pure
    financial investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#31 - A Dummy's Guide to Business Plan</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/dummys-guide-to-business-plan" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-31T17:16:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-10-31:dummys-guide-to-business-plan</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week is the mid-term exam week for GSB. It kicked off with &lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=GSBGEN+239%3A+Sloan%3A+Executive+Communication+Strategies&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;GSBGEN
239: Executive Communication Strategies'&lt;/a&gt;
individual presentation. I translated one of my old presentations on
Business Plan Writing from Chinese into English and just went with it.
The original presentation was first used in my talk in &lt;a href="http://www.cafa.edu.cn"&gt;China Central
Academy of Fine Arts (CAFA)&lt;/a&gt; to a class of
graduate students who wanted to learn more about the business world. For
a short 5-minute presentation, it's pretty heavily loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PPT follows Steve Jobs' school of "zen style" of ppt-making, with a
lot of inspirations from Garr Reynolds' wonderful book:&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Presentation-Zen-Simple-Design-Delivery/dp/0321525655"&gt;"Presentation
Zen"&lt;/a&gt;.
Basically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;full-background impactful pictures;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;as few words as possible;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;huge fonts;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/14974292?rel=0" width="800" height="651" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;" allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/gankyun/dummys-guide-to-business-plan" title="Dummy&amp;#x27;s Guide to Business Plan" target="_blank"&gt;Dummy&amp;#x27;s Guide to Business Plan&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/gankyun" target="_blank"&gt;Herbert Yang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#18_10 Reflections of a CFO</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/10-reflections-of-a-cfo" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-04T23:43:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-10-04:10-reflections-of-a-cfo</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today's &lt;a href="https://explorecourses.stanford.edu/search?view=catalog&amp;amp;filter-coursestatus-Active=on&amp;amp;page=0&amp;amp;catalog=&amp;amp;q=HISTORY+51K+-+Election+2012&amp;amp;collapse="&gt;Real-Life
Ethics&lt;/a&gt;,
our lecturers/serial entrepreneurs/Sand Hill venture capitalists &lt;a href="http://explorecourses.stanford.edu/CourseSearch/instructor?sunet=mleslie1"&gt;Mark
Leslie&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://peter.a16z.com"&gt;Peter Levine&lt;/a&gt; gave us another intriguing
case of dilemmas involving an SEC investigation and a CFO.  A few years
ago I was just like the protagonist in that case and experienced
something similar. Surviving from the dog-eat-dog world of China's
investment/startup world, there are a few reflections I can share with
my classmates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of CFO's job description says: take the blame for CEO and dodge
    the bullet for him, for the greater good of the company. CFOs of
    publicly-traded companies are all aware of this professional hazard
    when taking the job and understand this is one of the risks that
    just come with the package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only matters when either the CEO or the CFO gets fired, because
    they sign off on the company's financial statements. In most cases,
    the firing of anybody else in the executive leadership team does not
    matter (CXO, CTO, CSO, CIO... ) to SEC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CFO who gets fired in a highly publicized SEC investigation may
    experience difficulty in finding his/her way back to a similar post
    in another public company, but that does not spell the end of
    his/her professional career and sometimes hardly even matters. It's
    very situational and depends on the PR nature of the firing. If the
    CFO is only a sacrificial lamb to save the company, people in the
    industry usually know that. There is a fairly good chance that
    his/her reputation will remain intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many CFOs, jobs are not found through submitting resumes to
    random employers who don't share a mutual friend with him/her. If a
    future employer still has questions about this past SEC
    investigation, don't work for him and find somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CFOs are not hard to find; but great CFOs that can hold on his/her
    own against a volatile and inexperienced board are very hard to come
    by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Situations like this where the CFO is getting fired for saving the
    company/CEO presents an excellent opportunity for the CFO to
    negotiate the best deal (golden parachute, forgiven loan, escalated
    bonus) with the company. CFO has the most information and holds all
    the cards. He can talk to SEC to thoroughly destroy the company if
    his demands are not met. He brings very creditable threat in such
    negotiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not a bad idea for the CFO in such situation (the company is
    being investigated by SEC and the stock price tanks) to resign. If
    he doesn't resign =&amp;gt; the SEC investigation drags on =&amp;gt; the stock
    price plunges =&amp;gt; his options are all underwater =&amp;gt; no point for
    him to stay on anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the CFO should not volunteer to resign. Because doing so gives
    up his best negotiation opportunity. He should wait for the
    CEO/board to make a proposal to him and negotiate from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock ownership plan is not fair to the executives. Use options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company loans made to company executives are meant to be forgiven in
    practice. Don't make such loans. They are invitation for endless
    troubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>职业选择的考虑</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/career-choice-consideration" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-21T15:47:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2011-10-21:career-choice-consideration</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="257" height="33" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="http://www.xiami.com/widget/0_2960195/singlePlayer.swf" wmode="transparent"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以为自己N年前就写过这篇文章了，在网站上遍寻不获，为方便转发，只好重新码字。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在考虑换工作或者职业发展的下一步时，通常有这么几大因素需要考虑：老板，行业，地点，公司，职位，工作（工作环境，同事，交通，薪水，新技能。。。这些技术细节不是本文关注的焦点），按照重要性从高到低的排序如下：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;老板&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是最关键的因素，其重要性超过其他五项总和。跟对了人，其他所有问题都只是暂时的问题，都可以最终解决；跟错了人，则会陷入万丈深渊无法自拔。老板招人，但我们也在寻找最欣赏自己的伯乐，这个选择是双向的。人跟人之间的沟通很微妙，跟一个知己之间产生的化学作用可遇而不可求。遇上一个了解自己潜能，欣赏自己个性的老板，是万金难买的RP大爆发事件，要好好珍惜。在中国，这个因素尤其至关重要。一个好的老板，Ta的资源是跨行业跨地域的，可以带来无尽的新机会。在美国，这个因素的重要性稍微降低一些，因为美国地域太广阔（不像中国，大部分资源都集中在北京和上海），行业分化程度高，会削弱一个超级老板的影响力（但仍然是六项之首）。当目前的工作出现迷雾和不确定因素时，先看看老板的意向，看看你的下一步会对Ta产生什么样的影响，会帮助Ta解决什么样的问题，不要天真地一味从自己的利益角度出发考虑问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;行业&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;女怕嫁错郎，男怕入错行，这句话是公理。一个人的履历价值主要体现在两方面：行业经验/domain
expertise和功能技术/functional skills. 要达到行业顶端，domain
expertise是必要条件；到达了一个垂直行业的顶端后，可以凭借functional
skill进行跨行业的移动。Domain
expertise是靠一个工作一个工作积累起来的，频繁转行是大忌，青春时光只有二十年，也就经得起折腾个四五次，龟兔赛跑的道理浅显但常常被人遗忘。只有很少数的幸运儿在大学一毕业就能找到自己终身喜欢从事的事情，大多数人都需要经历几次行业的转变才会发现真爱。寻找自己热爱的事业，是一个更加宏大的终极命题，改日另行详述。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;地点&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;一个人三十岁以后的走势，社会关系是其主要推动力，而社会关系有极强的地域性。每次更换生活城市，所有的社会关系都得更新一遍，代价太大了。生活地点一旦定下来，买房，买车，都是迟早的规定动作，否则周围的人知道你是个浮萍，是个匆匆过客，不会在你身上投资过多的时间成本。对于想要回国的海外游子们，如果最终目的地是国内，则晚回不如早回。早一天回来，早一天开始积累人脉资源，没有其他捷径。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;公司&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;。。。没什么好说的，除了：行业比公司重要，公司跟职位之间的排序可以更换，但大多数时候公司比职位更重要，因为，公司比职位实在。很多时候，不同行业，不同公司里的看起来貌似相同的职业难以作比较，但公司之间是可以在品牌，美誉，规模上产生直接对比关系的。公司的存在感要比职位强烈得多。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;职位&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;职位的描述比较虚，表面上看不出来有什么不一样的地方，只有做了才知道，所以它的重要性也比较靠后。在很多行业里，有一些大家都公认的职位，这些职位的虚名可能比实际的工作性质更加重要。你要么做过，要么没做过，很多人就是凭照你的职位来定义你的能力。这虽然不是一个很公平的判断方法，但实际情况往往就是如此。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;工作&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;排名最后的，是你实际在做什么。这个因素调整起来相对比较容易，属于转变成本最低的。很多人的眼睛里就只盯着这个最浅显表象的因素，实在是本末倒置。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary><category term="中文"></category><category term="theory"></category></entry><entry><title>世说新语</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/real-meaning-of-English" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-29T01:53:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2010-06-29:real-meaning-of-English</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;这方面的书已经是汗牛充栋了，我也来凑凑热闹。以下是一些个人在公司里的感受。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a very good point&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shit you just caught me off guard with my pants down!/I totally
missed that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's do a deep dive into this area&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show me all the spreadsheets with the most gory details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me go socialize Tom&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let me talk to Tom and try to get his buy-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the MAN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks for the Starbucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey I'm getting some Starbucks...you want anything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I legitimately kiss you up?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(responded from above) Yeah ... actually... I'll go with you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to talk to you in private. Got some rumors/gossips to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this a good/bad guy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it favorable/unfavorable to net income?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah I hear you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand your concern and ... dear, I don't give a damn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretch line&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;difference between my bottom-up forecast and the top-down requirement
on net income which I have no clue whatsoever how to achieve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go figure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know how to do it and I don't care. Just do it. That's YOUR
job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oops how come I missed that / Yeah right ... big deal ... so what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah...right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gotta be kidding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be a bad idea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This idea sucks. You can't think of anything remotely intelligent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just want to plant some seeds here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give this idea some thought, though it's still too early to talk about
it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm just thinking out loud&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have this brilliant idea and you have to hear it... you may not
understand it though and it may not have anything to do with the debate
here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just throw it to the wall and see what sticks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we do this to them, they will get hurt, but I don't care. Do it.
Only worry about it when they respond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the shit hits the fan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When this whole thing blows up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start FYIing stuff to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start putting my name in the "cc" field and do not expect me to do any
action, though I might.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just between us girls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is just between you and me. It's totally unofficial and private.
(only used on guys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just want to make sure we are all on the same page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You so have no clue what this project is about. Let me explain it to
you, stupid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's just put some stakes in the ground&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know whether this action is right or wrong, but we have to do
something, now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently he's been prepped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somebody already briefed him of the agenda before he came to the
meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just want to throw it out there&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't know whether this works or not and I take no stand on this
issue, but it's worth a discussion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just hear me out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know you disagree, but heck let me finish my freaking sentence!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we just have to agree to disagree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I acknowledge we've tried to resolve the dispute and we remain
divided, but it's ok. Our disagreement is not a show-stopper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, fine... let's talk about the process and policy then&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are probably right on this one, but did you spell it out in the
standard operating procedure 152 section 47 paragraph 13? If not, I'll
do it my way. Go change the policy before picking up another fight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might want to have a closed-door conversation with Tom prior to the
meeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure Tom is totally silent and nods to whatever we say on the
meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't mind being a good soldier if this is the moment of
all-hands-on-deck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't agree and don't want to do this. But if you order me to do so
and this is going to help you, fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the moment of all-hands-on-deck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company is in trouble... EVERYONE has to contribute. Otherwise we
all go down the drain together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="中文"></category></entry><entry><title>Break Up GE To Unlock Its Value</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/break-up-GE-to-unlock-its-value" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-05-09T23:05:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2006-05-09:break-up-GE-to-unlock-its-value</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GE’s stock has been in a &lt;em&gt;5-year slump&lt;/em&gt; since 2001. Immelt’s got a tough job. He’s been relentlessly doing everything humanely possible to make the same GE sales pitch to analysts, major shareholders, the board, customers, employees, Dave Calhoun and himself. Fortune’s November issue runs a cover story on him and the photo displays his now completely-turned-silver hair. I recall his hair was mostly black when I saw him in Tokyo in mid–2001. Despite the best efforts from one of the best CEOs working today, investors are through buying it. GE stock is still going nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean while a noticeable &lt;em&gt;exodus&lt;/em&gt; is taking place with some of GE’s brightest executives. Cerberus Capital Management, the all-mighty hedge fund that trumped KKR in the then-landmark GMAC deal, has become a hub for GE alumni. GE managers, some of who report directly to Immelt’s staff (which means they have a legitimate shot at being CEO/CFO for many Fortune 500 companies, except for the top 20) , are quickly populating the ranks of various private equity and hedge fund firms. The exodus
reached alarming level when Dave Calhoun, a 27-year GE lifer who was once a front-runner in the horse race to succeed Jack Welch and now a vice chairman of the company, quitted in Aug 2006 to run a far smaller private media company VNU (backed by KKR, Blackstone and Carlyle), with a rumored $100MM potential incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much has been talked about the benefits of turning a company into a &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; one. The advantages are especially pronounced given today’s corporate governance activism (whether an ordinary man in the street agrees or not, some managers ARE worth hundreds of million dollars in
pay, not to mention private jet or Manhattan apartments) and Sarbanes Oxley Act. So my initial thought on how to salvage GE was on this path - what if we can LBO GE…? Well I quickly dismissed that myself. Indeed PE and Hedge Funds (the line to distinguish the two is fairly blur right now) are calling the shots all around, evidenced by the fact that the record for highest LBO deal has been set TWICE already in 2006, eclipsing the heyday of the greedy 80’s (on a side note, Lous Gestner - then in RJR Nabisco, is now back in the game with Carlyle, completing a full circle). Now they’re setting their eyes on Dell ($60BN) and Ford ($35BN). Only sky is the limit for those cowboys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However GE with $362BN market cap is clearly too much for &lt;em&gt;PE firms&lt;/em&gt; to make a run at. Besides the obvious financial hurdle, the current LBO model doesn’t fit for companies like GE or Apple. Among all others, the biggest change LBO brings to a public firm is that it puts a time stamp on the life of the company, which is otherwise presumed to exist in perpetuity. Live if you can make a change within the next five years; die if you can’t. That new corporate goal changes the entire mentality and easily solves the century-old agency problem. It makes a lot of sense if the company in its past life as a public entity is just an also-run. What if you’re already the market leader? What if your existence serves a higher purpose for the society at large, and for the sake for preserving mankind dignity your existence should be expected and allowed to last in perpetuity (Apple is an example; GE, hmm...arguably so)? Businesses of that nature probably won’t appreciate the short-term focus of PE firms, but ironically the structural advantages that PE firms can bring about are exactly what such businesses need so that they can: 1) focus on actually delivering the best products and services instead of utilizing management’s intellectual prowess in strategizing how to hit the EPS; 2) stop trying to figure out how to allocate income “stretch” targets; 3) leave the explanation of options backdating to accountants only; 4) forget about balancing double-digit growth in revenue, income, cash simultaneously while maintaining 20% ROE, which is a more formidable feat than proving Poincare Conjecture (go Perelman!); 5) sit down, have a cigar, and think about what is the next big thing that will reshape the planet and mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough said. So which model would fit GE? &lt;em&gt;Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/em&gt;’s is pretty close. Buffett essentially runs that as a private company - no meeting with street analysts, no earning forecast (if you don’t manage net income, how can you forecast? And then everyone says managing income is evil…duh?), no excessive sales pitch other than Buffett’s legendary annual letters. That culture is what GE needs to liberate its highly competent management team from numerous mundane short-term tasks and allow them to develop truly long-term vision and strategy for the company. Nonetheless, GE has another unique, insurmountable challenge - its size. Berkshire Hathaway has  $160BN market cap and GE’s more than twice of that. GE’s market cap has become so large and its business is so diversified (the bite for being the all-time champion for diversification), it’ll just take too much market movement to nudge itsstock price. Unless GE has a true blockbuster product (like the light bulb a century ago), investors can hardly get excited about its performance (some washing machine and x-ray machines every now and then ain’t enough). Over the years the giant company has turned into a process-driven business rather than product/service-driven one. Everybody knows GE will methodically meet its every target and continue to churn out excellent managers, but few know GE Capital alone can rival Citi Group, Bank of America and J.P. Morgan Chase in size and product offering. GE is paying the price for its own size - its far-ranging products and services are all excellent in their own right and market segments, but they are trivialized when everything is added up to form the sum of GE. There is a ton of value within each GE division it almost
seems that the entropy is lost or just cancelled out with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore IMHO the best way to unlock GE’s value is to &lt;em&gt;break it up&lt;/em&gt;. It can be split into six businesses - Commercial Finance, Consumer Finance, Infrastructure, Healthcare, Industrial and transportation. It’s not exactly a clean-cut but it’s doable. Some of those P&amp;amp;Ls will be innerly harmonized enough to form their own identity, culture and mission to go to greatness on their own. Some of them may be more challenged with an identity crisis, but they will survive. GE’s portfolio model (used to be callled SBU.. Anyone still remember?) has been extremely successful in
the past, and to this date is still the envy for many other companies. It has four major advantages, but I’ll argue none of them should be a show-stopper to break up GE. GE’s old model has four distinctive features. In today’s world, either they’re no longer valid, or they’re no longer part of cost of living to stay in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Human Resource Training&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People is the best product coming out of GE. Millions of young, ambitious professionals flock to GE’s leadership training programs for their assortment of business and management training that is unparalleled in the world, both in breadth and depth. Once you’re marked as an “A” player, you’re expected to move to a new location, join another division, take new role and responsibilities every 18 to 24 months (yeah your kids will be multi-lingual, cross-culturally attuned by birth right). However, given GE’s siiiiiiiize, even after break-up, the new baby-GEs will still have enough critical mass to provide training opportunities in almost the same magnitude. All of them are already bona fide global platforms. In addition, people start domain specialization fairly soon within 2–3 years after they join the company.
If I started out with NBC at Rockefeller Center, would I really want to accelerate my career in Cincinnati in GE Transportation (big plant there)? Well, I’m sure I can find equally appealing placement elsewhere in NBC Universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Capital Allocation / the science of levering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic mojo for GE that once dazzled many competitors.Some businesses like GE Industrial are cash cows that don’t make too much net income but generate cash consistently. GE consolidates that cash (the treasury operation is a wonder to behold) and throw that around in high-growth businesses to make acquisitions. It’s a very efficient use of capital and only possible when you have a mix of industrial/capital and “cash cow”/“star” businesses. I would very much like to indulge in a more detailed discussion of “levering” for people who still recall the basic corporate finance principles from Brealey and Myers, but I should probably stop right here since I’m not entirely sure such levering mechanism is public knowledge. Mr. Bill Gross from Pimco almost stepped on this in his 2002 crusade on GE. Long story short, GE recapitalized quickly in response to Gross’ assault, and that discretion on capital allocation among its myriad of businesses is now gone (there are other benefits of NOT doing that though). Also, there is so much liquidity in the market now - GE is no longer the privileged few who can amass large sum of capital on a minute’s notice (just think about Blackstone’s $20BN fund). This paragraph may have unintended gaps in logical reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Portfolio Diversification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old topic with a new twist in the age of ultra rapid value creation. Business 101 says that diversification is useless (“home-made” effect), and in fine print below it also says that “… except for GE”. GE has been the consummate poster-boy defending the value of diversification. It’s a simple premise: its 1,000+ businesses are all in different industry cycles; at any given point, some will do well and some will not. The good and bad cancel out each other and usually what is left is gravy. It is a good, almost risk-free strategy, but not a particularly exciting one. Andy Grove says “Only the Paranoid Survive” (btw, that book doesn’t offer that much insight really. The old man is repeating himself too much), I say " Only the Double-Down Survive“. GE’s diversification has created a false sense of safety. 10% year-over-year steady growth may suffice in the past 100 years, but it’s not going to cut it in the new
century when a garage business of 40 people can create  $1.6BN over 18 months. On the other hand, GE Capital raised many eyebrows when it quietly started dominating GE’s balance sheet and profit and loss statement left and right. Indeed, if every soul on the street looks at GE as a finance company, GE will have to carry the same inspiring PE ratio as those financial firms - not a pretty outlook (but in a way it’s already happening). Therefore GE has to”balance" its Capital business growth with that of its Industrial business. I say, if GE Capital can grow 30% a year, let it roll and maybe that’ll be more than enough to make up for a lower PE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;One Corporate Brand Image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another argument for one GE lies in the brand name of GE. This is a touchy subject and I hold tremendous pride for this name. However I would tentatively toy around some timid thoughts that may suggest GE’s size is approaching to a level that could diminish its image and brand recognition. If one think about “What is GE?”, an old tag line emerges “Bring Good Things to Life”. True, GE used to exist for betterment of mankind in general, and it actually carried out that mission fairly well. What does it mean today? With all the breakthroughs in consumer technology and unprecedented business models, it doesn’t mean a whole lot. GE has way too many products and services for average consumer to make out a sketch of what it really is. It’s not like Apple=Innovation+Cool, or Walmart=Evil Empire/The Only Mall That Matters For Your Neighbourhood, or Google=Wonder Boy Wandering in Wonderland. Regardless of whether those images are good or bad, they are engraved in people’s minds and investors can easily relate to them. Immelt saw the statement become a bit staled and hollow. He made a sweeping change in 2005, opting for “Imagination at Work”. Immelt is smart. He certainly felt the coming of an identity crisis. Do people really buy that? Only time will tell but I can at least argue that the inclusion of certain businesses do not necessarily inspire aura of “imagination” for average Joe. If GE were broken up into a few pieces, the new baby-GEs will be more recognizable with potentially more coherent messages to convey to their respective targeted customer segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To round up my 20 cents, going private will give GE much needed structural and process advantages to let it focus on running the business. Today’s PE models and Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway model provide bits of the elements that will be helpful to GE, but the transition from current GE to those models is beyond the capacity and
technology of today’s financial market (we need another Michael Milken). A detour that may get GE there and fully unlock GE’s value seems to be breaking it up into a few baby-GEs. It’s an audacious thought that challenges several conventional wisdoms built around GE’s success to date, but in today’s changed environment, those words of wisdom are in need for new validation and interpretation anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does that make any sense to you … no?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>