<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/journey.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://guizishanren.com/</id><updated>2014-06-02T08:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>First Bay to Breakers Run</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/first-bay-to-breakers-run" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-02T08:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-06-02:first-bay-to-breakers-run</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bay_to_Breakers"&gt;Bay to Breakers&lt;/a&gt; run is a world-famous running event in San Francisco. I had a good time doing my first one on May 18, 2014. Didn't dress up as any funky characters but had my fair share of running into eccentric animals, super heroes, and naked men. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/gankyun/14146036018" title="BaytoBreakers Record by herbertyang, on Flickr"&gt;&lt;img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3916/14146036018_0087639226_c.jpg" width="800" height="656" alt="BaytoBreakers Record"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#62 - Herbert's GCBC Talk</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/Herbert-GCBC-Talk" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-16T17:27:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-07-16:Herbert-GCBC-Talk</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was a organized by Stanford GSB's Greater China Business Student Club (thanks
to Xinkai and Rainey). The talk was scheduled during the final exam week
of the Spring Quarter between some terrifying exams. Thank you my
friends who showed up for this event and engaged me in a spirited
conversation about movies, rock band, flash mob, China, and leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/70445933?color=252525" width="800" height="534" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Weining who recorded the clip faithfully. This truncated
footage actually works out to be a reasonable self-introduction that I
can probably recycle for other occasions. It helps me to stay concise,
one of the qualities I'm still aspiring to work on.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="video"></category><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#55 - GCBC Talk - Stay Full Stay Smart</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/stay-full-stay-smart" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-28T00:19:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2013-05-28:stay-full-stay-smart</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GCBC Talk Series: &lt;em&gt;Stay Full, Stay Smart&lt;/em&gt;, by Herbert Yang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date:       May 29, Wednesday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time:           9-10pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venue:          Schwab Ferguson Lounge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crunching Tiger, Hidden Dragon&lt;/em&gt; - how was the Gangnam Style Flash
Mob born into GSB on Oct 12, 2012?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Wedding Banquet&lt;/em&gt; - how to manage a rock band?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hulk&lt;/em&gt; - a career from CFO to movie producer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sense and Sensibility&lt;/em&gt; - how to tell stories with your pictures?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eat Drink Man Woman&lt;/em&gt; - what are the drivers of your life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pushing Hands&lt;/em&gt; - How to manage career transition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ride with the Devil&lt;/em&gt; - What do you bring to the table, as a
leader?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brokeback Mountain&lt;/em&gt; - What are the different goals in GSB, in
Stanford, in any community&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lust, Caution&lt;/em&gt; - What exactly does a CFO do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life of Pi&lt;/em&gt; - Reflections of a sea turtle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Days of Being Wild&lt;/em&gt; - The good, the Bad, the Ugly of running
startups in Beijing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It'll be a casual talk. Given the crazy academic schedule this week, I
don't expect more than 10-15 people to show up. I'll pick up some topics
that the audience are most interested in, during this prolonged late
coffee break. I'll have Ang Lee to take care of the business part, and
maybe save Wong Kar Wai for the non-business part, for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidently, I was too bored.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>COASSF#35 - My BBL, My Choices</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/my-bbl" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-22T19:20:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-12-22:my-bbl</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;one-hour lunch session in one of our lecture rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brown Bag Lunch&lt;/em&gt;, or BBL in short, is a tradition in Stanford Sloan
Fellow Program and also in Stanford GSB at large. It's a lunch session
where everyone brings lunchbox and listens to a classmate's
self-introduction called BBL. BBL is to talk about yourself, let your
classmates understand better who you are, where you come from, and where
are you going (这是北大门卫的三个提问么？）. It's an open canvas and you
can freely draw up whatever you want, talk about whatever topics that
you think might be interesting for others to know. Usually one BBL goes
for 15 minutes and the program staff tries to have 4 BBLs during
one-hour lunch session in one of our lecture rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BBL is the single most valuable experience I have as a Sloan (except my
flash mob, except my half-time show, and except my rock band
debut...sorry for the excessive qualifiers...I've been busy). My Sloan
fellows have told some amazing stories. There are 81 Sloans in the
class, coming from more than 30 countries with prior experiences ranging
from corporate executives, investment bankers, serial entrepreneurs,
angel investors, government dignitaries to military officers and
scientific researchers. BBLs offer an excellent way for us to peek into
their past lives, their countries, how they grew up to become who they
are today, the monumental decisions that changed their life trajectories
and led them to Stanford, their families, their hobbies, their
aspirations beyond Stanford. The BBLs are not only a kaleidoscope into
multiple parallel universes we never know, but also a personal bonding
moment with the speakers. This event is Sloans-only, and the rule is
that whatever shared in BBLs stays in BBLs - no picture, no video, no
sharing. Such an exclusive setting leads us to some very private corners
sometimes. When that happens, we all know that's a special moment that
has bonded us together - the speaker and the audience, it's a trust that
will be shared for life, and it's a connection that will never be
replaced by any online social networks. On top of all these, BBLs are
also a lot of fun, and many are highly creative. Not too many of us ever
have the opportunity to have an audience of 80 friends who are equally
talented and accomplished and willing to spend 15 minutes just listening
to our own life stories. So the overachieving Sloans really put in
tremendous amount of work to make the BBL as memorable as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's my own BBL for those who missed it. There were a lot of things I
could talk about and it was a bit of a struggle to figure out what
should go into the BBL. In the end I skipped most of the usual topics
(family, travel, work, etc) and only talked about one topic: &lt;em&gt;choice&lt;/em&gt;.
I think the choices a person makes defines who he/she is, and I shared 3
choices I made in this BBL. The perfect lead-in music to open my BBL is
my monologue inspired by Ewan McGregor in Transpotting, which can be
found here: &lt;a href="http://site.douban.com/yangkun/"&gt;http://site.douban.com/yangkun/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without my narrative it's probably hard to understand what all this is
about, but as I said earlier, those moments can never be re-lived.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="coassf"></category></entry><entry><title>A New Business Card</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/a-new-business-card" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-10T01:13:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-12-10:a-new-business-card</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually when I procrastinate on something, I'll try to find ways to
amuse myself and keep myself motivated. As I was procrastinating on the
preparation for the upcoming Accounting and Global Strategy final exams
over the weekend, I thought it would be fun to design my own business
cards for the Seattle trip next week. The staff at Palo Alto Fedex
office on California Ave was extremely helpful and gave me all the
necessary instructions. So I came up with this design using good old
PowerPoint. It worked well. The proof sample looked pretty sleek. I
shall receive the actual cards by Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/bizcard_cover.png", width="600px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first came to Stanford GSB Sloan Program, I did not feel business
card was going to be of much use here in Stanford/the Bay area. The use
of business cards is not as prevalent as in China. Most people seem to
be content with getting a phone number/email by the end of a pleasant
conversation. It's not common to see people give out business cards
hard-selling themselves, at least not on Stanford campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="../../../../images/bizcard_back.png", width="600px"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, many Sloans still ordered the standard business cards
from Stanford Sloan Program, which has a nice Stanford logo.
Occasionally it's still useful, during info sessions or networking
events like Tailgate parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our Seattle company visit trip next week, more than 60 Sloans
will be meeting with alumni and executives from various companies. The
thought of so many of us giving out almost identical business cards to
the same VIP made me wonder, maybe this is the time to get creative. I
need to figure out a way to distinguish myself from others, and I should
use my business card as the most potent vehicle for my personal branding
- a subject that has been the center of attention among me, my brother
&lt;a href="http://www.steve-qing-yang.com/"&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt;, and some old and new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here it is. The font is primarily Helvetica. The color for the cover
is tangerine. The "cloud" on the back took some painstaking effort to
complete - it was done manually by aligning every textbox into the right
position with the right color and font size, all in PowerPoint.
PowerPoint does a rather appalling job in rendering fonts. Some fonts
looked pretty goofy when the size was below 8. Fortunately PDF saved the
day. When I saved the PPT file as a PDF (on my Macbook Air), magically
PDF rendered all the fonts in their 100% glory and accuracy. Voila!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>Why Here, Why Now, Why Again?</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/why-here-why-now-why-again" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-27T23:33:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-09-27:why-here-why-now-why-again</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I guess I owe an explanation to many of my friends who have watched and
followed me with curiosity through all these years and numerous avant
garden social networks.  I've moved back to the States since June and I
haven't got the chance to call up many friends (actually, most) in the
States yet to let them know of this news, which is very uncharacteristic
of me. On the other side of the ocean, many of my friends in China are
wondering why I suddenly disappeared in Beijing's social scene. The
questions I've got a lot lately are: &lt;em&gt;Why are you here in Stanford? Why
are you back to the States? Why are you moving your home base again?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly I was a bit jaded explaining my recent endeavor to my
friends, who constitute a fairly substantial group across the Pacific.
Our annual newsletter at the end of the year still serves as an
effective way to keep all our cared ones updated - a tradition we have
been practicing since 2004 when living in Boston. However I stopped
writing the English version of the newsletter two years ago because a
Chinese version alone already exhausted all my creativity and
inspiration (I don't think any English newsletter can beat my Chinese
&lt;a href="http://www.guizishanren.com/?p=549"&gt;newsletter of 2010&lt;/a&gt; and 2011.
They're not as good as Umberto Eco's, but they are decent and pride
attempts in that direction). The problem with the newsletter is that
we've moving our lives too fast for the newsletter to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feeble attempt on Sina Weibo also got buried in the sea of tweets
quickly. I wrote
this&lt;a href="http://weibo.com/1270520763/ykmem37YZ"&gt;《出师表·2012》&lt;/a&gt;in May 22,
but Sina Weibo already started its irreversible decline and much fewer
users are still active. Nothing of much substance can really leave a
trail on twitter-esque Sina Weibo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's my latest update and why everything leads to right here, right
now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've had US greencard since 2006. My wife and I actually gave up
Singapore PR (permanent residence) after we got greencards (looking back
that was probably not a smart idea, from a personal tax standpoint)
thinking that US Greencard was all that we needed. When I left Boston to
join a tech startup in Beijing in 2008, I sort of gave up Greencard
mentally, expecting to settle down in Beijing in years to come. We did
settle down in Beijing and lived there for more than four years, during
which I joined two ambitious startup companies working with some of the
most influential VC firms. For a variety of reasons that can easily fill
up my first novel and two long and exciting TV drama series, these two
companies couldn't complete its IPO. So at the end of 2011 I was
weighing other options going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then as we were trying to enter US for our West Coast Highway 101 road
trip, we found that our greencard status faced serious challenge because
we did not stay physically inside US long enough. Long story short,
after consulting multiple immigration lawyers in the Bay area, we saw
two options in front of us with no middle-ground: either we move our
home base here, or we run the risk of giving up greencard on our next
trip back to US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn't want to give up greencard, so we decided to move back to US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving back to US seems to be against the current trend, as many Chinese
have flocked to Beijing, Shanghai and Hong Kong in recent years to
pursue their wild wild east dreams. US was still recovering slowly from
the painful sub-prime crisis since 2008 and China has been rising fast
into a superpower, at least economically. Colorful and exciting
rugs-to-riches stories roll off tongues in the bars and Starbucks in
Beijing and Shanghai while young people fantasize being the next Jack
Ma, Pony Ma, Robin Li, or Neil Shen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However there are certain things that we value very much and we find
very hard to come by in the environment where we became so intimate with
in the last few years. I won't go into details here though. Come to
Stanford and we can exchange some thoughts over a few glasses of
Zinfandel. The only thing I wouldn't mind sharing here is tax, because
it seems to be the first thing that comes to mind for many friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US is perceived to be a very high-taxed country, which is largely true.
Nonetheless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China's tax rate is just as high as US&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China's tax laws' development in recent years is clearly on a
    trajectory to becoming more and more like US tax laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technically China also taxes its residents on a global basis, just
    like US does. It's obviously very hard to enforce, but its
    principles are very similar to those of US tax laws&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US' tax rate is indeed very high for salaried workers, but if you
    work for yourself as an entrepreneur, you can maintain a fairly low
    effective tax rate. Romney famously has a tax rate of only 14%.
    Buffett keeps complaining his tax rate is too low.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, US' tax laws are well developed and there are
    many vehicles you can explore to bring down your effective tax laws.
    China's tax laws are far behind in sophistication. Some people might
    roll their eyes now and say I can get a lot of "gray" income in
    China through cash. Yes that's true. If that's your cup of tea or if
    you work in government departments/agencies, by all means stay where
    you are. Good for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are actually benefits associated with paying high tax rate in
    US - you get the best protection of your personal assets. At a
    certain point in our lives,  tax rate is really not the top concern.
    Easy come, easy go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After making up our mind to move over, we thought West Coast would be a
better choice as it's closer to Beijing/Shanghai with non-stop flight.
The weather is also much nicer on the west. Most importantly Silicon
Valley is here, where I can start from scratch to continue/pursue my
entrepreneurial ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I talked to friends in the Bay area to find out the startup scene in
the valley, I asked them what would be a necessary factor to startup
success. Invariably the answer was college network (company network has
little use, unless you've made a lot of money together with a
single-digit employ ID number). This sounds like a sad sad reality for
me since my alma mater is National University of Singapore (NUS). NUS is
an excellent university and it had huge influence over me in my
formative years, however its network in the US is fairly limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last day in Palo Alto during our Jan 2012 California trip, we
drove to Sand Hill Road on a pilgrimage to take a look at some of the
legendary venture capital firms here. Standing outside Andreessen
Horowitz's office looking at the sunset, I thought about that afternoon
of 12 years ago when &lt;a href="http://www.steve-qing-yang.com"&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt; brought me
here for the first time and showed me around. KPCB was there, so
unassuming and low-profiled. I had no idea what KPCB was yet at that
time, but I remembered Steve told me the day would come when I shall
come back here to raise capital from those most prestigious and powerful
investment firms in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So...just like that, an idea naturally stroke us, why not go to
Stanford, which is right here in the heart of Silicon Valley with the
best alumni network there is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew about &lt;a href="http://www.gsb.stanford.edu/sloan"&gt;Stanford's Sloan
Fellow&lt;/a&gt; program from a good friend
who graduated there in 2010. I  just never pictured myself in this
program because until very recently  I was very much immersed in the
crazy and non-stop business and social life in Beijing. Now all of a
sudden, coming to Stanford seems to make all the senses of the world. I
would not want to be anywhere but Silicon Valley and which university
would serve as a better platform to usher me into the startup and
investment circles of the valley?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this seed had been planted, the rest of the execution was fairly
easy. The past four years in Beijing saw tremendous professional and
personal growth for me. I've been through a lot. Maybe I'm yet to figure
out what works best, but at least I've known enough what does not work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am, in Stanford Graduate Business School's Sloan Fellow
program. My decision on Stanford was straightforward because it was
significantly &lt;a href="http://www.guizishanren.com/?p=871"&gt;location-based&lt;/a&gt;,
which was by the way in sharp contrast to my friend &lt;a href="http://sten.tamkivi.com/2012/02/why-and-how-i-became-a-stanford-student/"&gt;Sten's highly
methodological and scientific
approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many friends would ask me, so... is this move going to be permanent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know, my friend. I really don't know. When we lived in
Cambridge, MA, we loved Charles River, Cambridge and Boston, and never
thought about leaving there. When we moved to Beijing and bought a house
there, we thought Beijing was the best place for us. We seem to have a
blast everywhere and tend to live our lives to the fullest in general,
regardless of where we are.  When we moved here... I no longer want to
make any speculation and I no longer have any concept of "permanent" or
"temporary". We live our lives, day by day. Carpe diem in Stanford!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>出师表 - 2012</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/poem-leaving-Beijing" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-22T16:16:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2012-05-22:poem-leaving-Beijing</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;吾本桂子山人，躬耕于南洋，戎马倥偬于欧美，不求闻达于纳斯&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;贵人不以吾学浅，慧眼识才，二顾吾于酒店大堂之中，托吾以当市之事，由是感激，遂许贵人以驱使&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;后值江湖汹涌，受任于敲钟之际，奉命于融资之间，知春露晓，上东夕照，尔来四年有半矣！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;众友知吾志远趣广，故频频寄吾以大事也&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;入京以来，夙夜笙歌，恐音调不效，以伤众友之托，故广结英豪，深入战壕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;今这里已定，燕南已足&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;当怀揣三P，东渡西岸，再创辉煌，直捣谷底，联合资本，扩展项目，还于旧愿&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此吾所以报众友之望而忠众友之职分也&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;至于京华烟云，把酒言欢，则青山不改，绿水长流也&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;今当远离，临表涕零，不知所言&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="中文"></category><category term="诗歌"></category></entry><entry><title>Good Bye......Until We Meet Again</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/leaving-GE" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-08-15T18:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2007-08-15:leaving-GE</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;to be a trained Jedi Knight wielding a light saber to save the day every
8.0 months and I'm supposed to be pretty cool about all these moving-around. Guess I've gone soft over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day in GE. I've decided to veer away from the beaten
path and indulge myself in some of my long-term passion and interests.
GE has given me every professional skill I have and its affiliation
accounts for 62.78% of all my friends. So, it means a lot to me. What
makes my eight years of GE experience such a joy ride is you,
unmistakably you. Thank you for being there with me. Thank you for the
good times and I hope to continue them in the future. Well, I'm supposed
to be a trained Jedi Knight wielding a light saber to save the day every
8.0 months and I'm supposed to be pretty cool about all these
moving-around. Guess I've gone soft over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to give me a buzz at 1-617-852-6594(cell), if you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stop by Republic of Cambridge - I mean, Boston&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;struggling with some monumental Mac-vs-PC decision - Steve Jobs really owes me, like, a lo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not sure what movies to watch for the weekend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can't decide between a Stevie Wonder concert and a Smashing Pumpkins one - fantasize about going to Alaska, Tibet, Santorini, Paris, Provence or
Italy but need convincing photo evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ponder over some really stupid and absurd ideas about technology, media and entertainment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wondering OMG what is going on in China and want to get a train ride,
literally and figuratively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or just anything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I believe a non-company email address lays down a solid
foundation for long-term relationship. Please send me your personal one
(if you don't have one yet then get one). If you prefer any other means
(skype, gtalk, MSN, yahoo, linkedin, facebook, lunch...), just let me
know. I do all communication methods known to man from 19th to 22nd
century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inescapably, it's time for me to go. Good bye!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term=""></category></entry></feed>