<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>the Good the Bad and the Curious</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/feeds/pages.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://guizishanren.com/</id><updated>2014-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>About This Site</title><link href="http://guizishanren.com/posts/2014/03/about-this-site/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Herbert Yang</name></author><id>tag:guizishanren.com,2014-03-25:posts/2014/03/about-this-site/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm in the process of migrating this site from the previous &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/"&gt;wordpress&lt;/a&gt; structure to &lt;a href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github Page&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; static website generator. You might see some missing files, broken links, or just out-of-alignment here and there. That's because I'm still cleaning up the files from their xml format to streamline everything into strictly &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; format. If you have been a reader of my site before, there is no new content created after Mar 21, 2014. What gives then? Not a lot for you, but a great deal to me. I will write an article about this transformation later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you find any error or any format that you think is less than perfect in any page, please feel free to leave a comment on that page or this page so that I can fix it right away. Thank you in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is the publishing platform for all contents created by &lt;a href="www.linkedin.com/in/herbertyang‎"&gt;me&lt;/a&gt;, which includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;blog articles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;photo galleries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;performance videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;slide presentations &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain name "guizishanren" is "&lt;em&gt;桂子山人&lt;/em&gt;" in Chinese, of which the literal translation will be "The Person from Mt. Sweet Olive". Mt. Sweet Olive in Wuhan, China is where I grew up in China. Wuhan is about 1.5 hour by flight to both Beijing and Shanghai, and is the largest city in Central China who almost became and definitely should have become the capital city of China in 1949. It was a tragedy afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of this site pays tribute to movie "&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0060196/?ref_=nv_sr_2"&gt;The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly&lt;/a&gt;" by great &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001466/?ref_=tt_ov_dr"&gt;Sergio Leone&lt;/a&gt;, one of the greatest movies of all time. The soundtrack is just as epic and has become a frequent rip-off target by Quentin Tarantino ever since. Here's Metallica cover of the most famous song from the soundtrack, "&lt;em&gt;The Ecstasy of Gold&lt;/em&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="480" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/JG62B_dHfDQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this site takes a lot of patience and probably not a walk in the park. Thank you for stopping by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herbert&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>